[
    {
        "id": "OP11-001",
        "title": "OP11-001 Koby",
        "question": "Q: If 2 of my {Navy} type Characters with 7000 base power or less would be removed from the field by the [On Play] effect of my opponent's \"OP01-094 Kaido\", can I use this Leader's [Once Per Turn] effect to prevent both Characters from being K.O.'d? If so, do I place 3 cards or 6 cards from my trash at the bottom of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. The amount of cards you place at the bottom of your deck from your trash will be 3 regardless of how many Characters would be removed from your field."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-001",
        "title": "OP11-001 Koby",
        "question": "Q: If I have 2 or less cards in my trash and my {Navy} type Character with 7000 base power or less would be removed from the field, can I use this Leader's [Once Per Turn] effect to prevent my Characters from being removed from the field?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-001",
        "title": "OP11-001 Koby",
        "question": "Q: 2 of my {Navy} type Characters with 7000 base power or less, [Character A] and [Character B], were K.O.'d at the same time when I had 2 cards in my trash. In this case, can I first trash [Character A], then use this Leader's [Once Per Turn] effect to prevent [Character B] from being removed from the field?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-010",
        "title": "OP11-010 Hibari",
        "question": "Q: During my turn, if my opponent has a rested \"OP01-051 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid\" with a given DON!! card on their field, can my Leader, which can attack active Characters due to this card's [When Attacking] effect, attack my opponent's active Characters other than [Eustass\"Captain\"Kid]?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-012",
        "title": "OP11-012 Franky",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's effect if my opponent activates an Event's [Trigger] effect during my turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-012",
        "title": "OP11-012 Franky",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent activates \"OP01-026 Gum-Gum Fire-Fist Pistol Red Hawk\" during my turn, can I prevent this Character from being K.O.'d by the [Counter] effect of \"Gum-Gum Fire-Fist Pistol Red Hawk\" by activating this Character's effect first and increasing its power to 6000?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The Event's effect will be resolved before this card's effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-012",
        "title": "OP11-012 Franky",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent activates \"OP01-026 Gum-Gum Fire-Fist Pistol Red Hawk\" and K.O.'s this Character during my turn, can I still activate this Character's effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-013",
        "title": "OP11-013 Prince Grus",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [When Attacking] effect, and afterwards my opponent played a Character with 2000 power or less in the same turn. Will that Character be able to activate [Blocker] during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-013",
        "title": "OP11-013 Prince Grus",
        "question": "Q: My opponent's Character had 3000 power or more when I activated this [When Attacking] effect, but its power subsequently dropped to 2000 or less. Will it still be able to activate [Blocker] during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, in this case it will be able to activate [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-013",
        "title": "OP11-013 Prince Grus",
        "question": "Q: My opponent's Character had 2000 power or less when I activated this [When Attacking] effect, but its power subsequently rose to 3000 or more. Will it still be able to activate [Blocker] during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, in this case it will be unable to activate [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-014",
        "title": "OP11-014 Borsalino",
        "question": "Q: If I select a Character I played this turn as the target of this [Activate: Main] effect, will that Character be able to attack active Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not. This effect allows the selected Leader or Character to attack active Characters. However, because you cannot declare an attack with a Character on the turn it is played, the Character in question will not be able to attack active Characters."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-018",
        "title": "OP11-018 Honesty Impact",
        "question": "Q: When activating this [Main] effect, can I choose to give one Character −4000 power, then choose a different Character to K.O.?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-022",
        "title": "OP11-022 Shirahoshi",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Activate: Main] effect if my topmost Life card is already face-up?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-023",
        "title": "OP11-023 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: If this card in my hand has been given −3 cost due to this effect, can I play this card using the effects of \"OP11-024 Aladine\" or \"OP011-035 Fisher Tiger\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-024",
        "title": "OP11-024 Aladine",
        "question": "Q: When this Character is K.O.'d by my opponent's effect, can I choose to trash 1 card from my hand but not rest 1 of my DON!! cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must either choose to trash 1 card from your hand and rest 1 of your DON!! cards, or choose to do neither. If you choose to do neither, the effects after \"If you do...\" will not resolve."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-034",
        "title": "OP11-034 Hatchan",
        "question": "Q: Do effects that read \"cannot be rested\" mean that the affected Characters cannot attack?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the affected Characters cannot attack.These effects make the affected Characters unable to perform any actions that require them to be rested, such as attacking or activating [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-034",
        "title": "OP11-034 Hatchan",
        "question": "Q: Do effects that read \"cannot be rested\" mean that the affected Characters cannot activate effects such as \"[Activate: Main] You may rest this Character:\" and other similar effects?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the affected Characters cannot activate those effects.These effects make the affected Characters unable to perform any actions that require them to be rested, such as attacking or activating [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-034",
        "title": "OP11-034 Hatchan",
        "question": "Q: Do effects that read \"cannot be rested\" mean that the affected Characters cannot activate [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the affected Characters cannot activate [Blocker].These effects make the affected Characters unable to perform any actions that require them to be rested, such as attacking or activating [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-034",
        "title": "OP11-034 Hatchan",
        "question": "Q: Do effects that read \"cannot be rested\" mean that the affected Characters cannot become rested by the effects of your or your opponent's other cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the affected Characters cannot be rested by the effects of other cards.These effects make the affected Characters unable to perform any actions that require them to be rested, such as attacking or activating [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-040",
        "title": "OP11-040 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Do I activate this effect before or after drawing a card at the start of my turn?",
        "answer": "A: You activate this effect before drawing a card. The effect is activated at the beginning of your Refresh Phase which is resolved as follows: \"Effects that activate at the start of your turn → All given DON!! cards are returned to your cost area → All rested cards become active → Draw Phase\"."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-040",
        "title": "OP11-040 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect when I have 7 or less DON!! cards on my field?",
        "answer": "A: You can, but nothing will happen as you do not meet the effect's condition of \"If you have 8 or more DON!! cards on your field\"."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-041",
        "title": "OP11-041 Nami",
        "question": "Q: Can I also activate this [Your Turn] effect when a card is removed from my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. This effect can be activated regardless of whether the card is removed from your Life cards or your opponent's Life cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-041",
        "title": "OP11-041 Nami",
        "question": "Q: During my turn, I used the [On Play] effect of \"OP06-106 Kouzuki Hiyori\" to add a card from my Life cards to my hand, then add a card from my hand to my Life cards. Can I activate this Leader's [Your Turn] effect at this time?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-041",
        "title": "OP11-041 Nami",
        "question": "Q: During my turn, I used the [On Play] effect of \"EB01-052 Viola\" to look at all of my opponent's Life cards and place them back in their Life area in any order. Can I activate this Leader's [Your Turn] effect at this time?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-043",
        "title": "OP11-043 Vinsmoke Ichiji",
        "question": "Q: I have this Character and a Character that does not have a type including \"GERMA\" on my field. If my opponent's Character attacks, and my Character that does not have a type including \"GERMA\" is removed from the field due to its [When Attacking] effect or a similar effect, can I activate this Character's [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-044",
        "title": "OP11-044 Vinsmoke Judge",
        "question": "Q: If I play a {GERMA 66} type Character after activating this [Activate: Main] effect, will that Character also gain +1000 power during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-049",
        "title": "OP11-049 Carrot",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent's Character attacks, and this Character is removed from the field due to its [When Attacking] effect or a similar effect, can I still activate this Character's [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-057",
        "title": "OP11-057 Pedro",
        "question": "Q: This Character gained [Blocker] from this effect and activated it when my opponent attacked. However, during the Counter Step, my hand reached 5 or more cards, causing it to lose [Blocker]. In this case, will the card that was originally targeted for attack become the target again?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-058",
        "title": "OP11-058 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent activated the [On Play] effect of \"OP08-043 Edward.Newgate\" during their previous turn, and I have 6 cards in my hand during my turn, can I attack with this Character by trashing 2 cards from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-059",
        "title": "OP11-059 Gum-Gum King Cobra",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this card's [Counter] effect when I have 5 cards in my hand including this card, how much power will my Leader or Character card gain?",
        "answer": "A: Your Leader or Character card will gain +4000 power. When you activate an Event card, that Event card is not counted as part of your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-066",
        "title": "OP11-066 Charlotte Oven",
        "question": "Q: If the card revealed with this [Activate: Main] effect does not have the chosen cost, what happens with the effect \"add up to 1 DON!! card from your DON!! deck and rest it\"?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, you cannot add DON!! cards from your DON!! deck or K.O. up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a base cost of 3 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-072",
        "title": "OP11-072 Charlotte Mont-d'or",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has 1 card in their trash, can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to place that 1 card from their trash at the bottom of their deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-082",
        "title": "OP11-082 Aramaki",
        "question": "Q: If I select a Character I played this turn as the target of this [Activate: Main] effect, will that Character be able to attack active Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not. This effect allows the selected Leader or Character to attack active Characters. However, because you cannot declare an attack with a Character on the turn it is played, the Character in question will not be able to attack active Characters."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-083",
        "title": "OP11-083 Caribou",
        "question": "Q: If I have 1 or less cards in my hand, can I still play this Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, this [On Play] effect will mean that you trash the 1 card in your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-084",
        "title": "OP11-084 Kuzan",
        "question": "Q: If I select a Character I played this turn as the target of this [When Attacking] effect, will that Character be able to attack active Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not. This effect allows the selected Leader or Character to attack active Characters. However, because you cannot declare an attack with a Character on the turn it is played, the Character in question will not be able to attack active Characters."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-086",
        "title": "OP11-086 Coribou",
        "question": "Q: If I have 0 cards in my hand, can I still play this Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-091",
        "title": "OP11-091 Berry Good",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has 2 or less Events in their trash, will this [On Play] effect mean that my opponent places all the Event cards from their trash at the bottom of their deck?",
        "answer": "A: A: Yes, it does. In this case, your opponent will place all the Events in their trash at the bottom of their deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-092",
        "title": "OP11-092 Helmeppo",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [On Play] effect to discard 1 {SWORD} type Character card with a cost of 8 or less other than [Helmeppo], can I then play that card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-097",
        "title": "OP11-097 After All These Years I'm Losing My Edge!!!",
        "question": "Q: During the Counter Step, I used a black Character card with a cost of 3 or less as a counter, and then activated this [Counter] effect while having 10 or more cards in my trash. In this case, can I add the black Character card with a cost of 3 or less that I just used as a counter to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-097",
        "title": "OP11-097 After All These Years I'm Losing My Edge!!!",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [Counter] effect when I have 9 cards in my trash, can I still add a black Character card with a cost of 3 or less from my trash to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-102",
        "title": "OP11-102 Camie",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent activates \"OP01-026 Gum-Gum Fire-Fist Pistol Red Hawk\" and K.O.'s this Character during my turn, can I still activate this Character's effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-102",
        "title": "OP11-102 Camie",
        "question": "Q: If I deal 1 damage to my opponent when they have 2 Life cards and my opponent activates a [Trigger] effect, can I still activate this [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, as the card that activated the [Trigger] effect will be removed from your opponent's Life cards, the number of your opponent's Life cards will become 1, so nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-102",
        "title": "OP11-102 Camie",
        "question": "Q: I dealt damage to my opponent when they had 2 Life cards, and my opponent activated the [Trigger] effect of \"OP05-115 Two-Hundred Million Volts Amaru\", adding 1 card from the top of their deck to the top of their Life cards. In this case, can I use this [Your Turn] effect to trash 1 card from the top of each of my and my opponent's Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-102",
        "title": "OP11-102 Camie",
        "question": "Q: My opponent's Leader is \"OP05-098 Enel.\" If I deal damage to my opponent when they have 1 Life card and my opponent activates the [Trigger] effect of \"OP06-115 You're the One Who Should Disappear,\" in what order do this [Your Turn] effect and my opponent's Enel's effect resolve?",
        "answer": "A: As the turn player's effects take priority, this card's effect will activate first, followed by Enel's effect. When this effect is activated, nothing will happen because your opponent's only Life card is the one added by the [Trigger] effect of \"You're the One Who Should Disappear.\". Then, your opponent will add 1 card from the top of their deck to the top of their Life cards and trash 1 card from their hand due to Enel's effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP11-119",
        "title": "OP11-119 Koby",
        "question": "Q: If I select a Character I played this turn as the target of this [On Play] effect, will that Character be able to attack active Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not. This effect allows the selected Leader or Character to attack active Characters. However, because you cannot declare an attack with a Character on the turn it is played, the Character in question will not be able to attack active Characters."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-001",
        "title": "EB01-001 Kouzuki Oden",
        "question": "Q: I had a {Land of Wano} type Character card with a cost of 5 or more when I activated this [When Attacking] effect and this Leader gained +1000 power. If I no longer have a {Land of Wano} type Character with a cost of 5 or more during my opponent's next turn, does this Leader still have +1000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it still has +1000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-003",
        "title": "EB01-003 Kid & Killer",
        "question": "Q: If this Character gains +2000 power according to this [When Attacking] effect, and then during that turn the number of my opponent's Life cards becomes 3, does this Character still have +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it still has +2000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-008",
        "title": "EB01-008 LittleOars Jr.",
        "question": "Q: Can this [Once Per Turn] effect prevent this Character from being K.O.'d by an effect even if I don't have an Event or Stage card in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-011",
        "title": "EB01-011 Mini-Merry",
        "question": "Q: Can I place a Character with 1000 base power but a current power of 2000 or more due to having DON!! cards given to it at the bottom of my deck and draw 1 card according to this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-012",
        "title": "EB01-012 Cavendish",
        "question": "Q: If I do not have an \"EB01-012 Cavendish\" on my field, but I do have 1 \"OP01-008 Cavendish\", and I play an \"EB01-012 Cavendish\", can I use this [On Play] effect to set 2 of my DON!! cards as active?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-020",
        "title": "EB01-020 Chambres",
        "question": "Q: If I have no Characters, can I use this [Main] effect to play a Character card with a cost of 2 or less from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-021",
        "title": "EB01-021 Hannyabal",
        "question": "Q: If I have no cards in my DON!! deck, can I use this [End of Your Turn] effect to return 1 of my {Impel Down} type Characters with a cost of 2 or more to the owner's hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-022",
        "title": "EB01-022 Inazuma",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader is \"OP02-049 Emporio.Ivankov\" and I have no cards in my hand at the end of my turn, after drawing 2 cards according to that Leader's [End of Your Turn] effect, can I use this card's [End of Your Turn] effect to draw 2 more cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-024",
        "title": "EB01-024 Hamlet",
        "question": "Q: If I have 4 or less cards in my hand, does this card gain +1000 power according to this card's effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-028",
        "title": "EB01-028 Gum-Gum Champion Rifle",
        "question": "Q: Which player chooses which Character to return to the owner's hand according to this [Counter] effect?",
        "answer": "A: The opponent of the player who activated this [Counter] effect chooses."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-028",
        "title": "EB01-028 Gum-Gum Champion Rifle",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have the {Impel Down} type, can I still use this [Counter] effect to have my opponent return 1 of their active Characters to the owner's hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-029",
        "title": "EB01-029 Sorry. I'm a Goner.",
        "question": "Q: If the cost of the card revealed according to this [Counter] effect is 3 or less, what happens to the revealed card?",
        "answer": "A: The revealed card is returned face-down to the top of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-038",
        "title": "EB01-038 Oh Come My Way",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Counter] effect to change my opponent's attack target to my active Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-038",
        "title": "EB01-038 Oh Come My Way",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [Counter] effect to change my opponent's attack target to a Character with [Blocker], can that Character activate its [Blocker] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-040",
        "title": "EB01-040 Kyros",
        "question": "Q: If the card at the top of my Life cards is face-up, can I still use this [Activate: Main] effect to K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 0?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-042",
        "title": "EB01-042 Scarlet",
        "question": "Q: I used this [Activate: Main] effect to play an \"OP04-082 Kyros\" from my hand, and then gave 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 3 −2 cost. Can I use the [On Play] effect of my played \"OP04-082 Kyros\" to K.O. my opponent's Character that has been given −2 cost?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-045",
        "title": "EB01-045 Brook",
        "question": "Q: If, after this Character gains [Rush] according to this [On Play] effect, my opponent no longer has a Character with a cost of 0 during that turn, can this Character still attack?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-047",
        "title": "EB01-047 Laboon",
        "question": "Q: If only this 1 Character is K.O.'d, can I activate this Character's \"When a Character is K.O.'d\" effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-051",
        "title": "EB01-051 Finger Pistol",
        "question": "Q: If I have 1 or less cards in my deck, can I use this [Main] effect to trash my deck and K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 5 or less?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-052",
        "title": "EB01-052 Viola",
        "question": "Q: When I use this [On Play] effect to look at all of my opponent's Life cards and place them back in their Life area in any order, do I return the face-up Life cards face-down?",
        "answer": "A: No. You return face-down Life cards face-down, and face-up Life cards face-up."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-052",
        "title": "EB01-052 Viola",
        "question": "Q: When I use this [On Play] effect to turn all of my Life cards face-down, can I change the order of my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-059",
        "title": "EB01-059 Kingdom Come",
        "question": "Q: If I have 1 or less Life cards, does this [Main] effect increase or decrease my number of Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not change the number of Life cards you have."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-059",
        "title": "EB01-059 Kingdom Come",
        "question": "Q: I had 2 Life cards and my opponent had 2 Life cards when my Leader took 1 damage. At this time, if the card I check on the top of my Life cards is this card, can I use this [Trigger] effect to K.O. my opponent's Character with a cost of 4?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. In this case, you can use this [Trigger] effect to K.O. your opponent's Character with a cost of 3 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-060",
        "title": "EB01-060 Did Someone Say...Kami?",
        "question": "Q: If I have 1 Life card or less, does this [Main] effect increase or decrease my number of Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not change the number of Life cards you have."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB01-061",
        "title": "EB01-061 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)",
        "question": "Q: When I use this Character to attack with 1 DON!! card given to it and I choose 1 of my opponent's Characters with 5000 power according to this [When Attacking] effect, does this Character's power become 6000?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it becomes 6000."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-006",
        "title": "EB02-006 Yamato",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have the {Land of Wano} type and its card name is not \"Portgas.D.Ace\", can this Character still gain [Rush] from this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-010",
        "title": "EB02-010 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: What does this [Activate: Main] effect do if I have 0 Characters on my field?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, after you choose to return 2 DON!! cards to your DON!! deck with this [Activate: Main] effect, nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-011",
        "title": "EB02-011 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: Do effects that read \"cannot be rested\" mean that the affected Characters cannot attack?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, affected Characters cannot attack.These effects make the affected Characters unable to perform any actions that require them to be rested, such as attacking or activating [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-011",
        "title": "EB02-011 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: Do effects that read \"cannot be rested\" mean that the affected Characters cannot activate effects such as \"[Activate: Main] You may rest this Character:\" and other similar effects?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the affected Characters cannot activate those effects.These effects make the affected Characters unable to perform any actions that require them to be rested, such as attacking or activating [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-011",
        "title": "EB02-011 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: Do effects that read \"cannot be rested\" mean that the affected Characters cannot activate [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the affected Characters cannot activate [Blocker].These effects make the affected Characters unable to perform any actions that require them to be rested, such as attacking or activating [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-011",
        "title": "EB02-011 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: Do effects that read \"cannot be rested\" mean that the affected Characters cannot become rested by the effects of your or your opponent's other cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the affected Characters cannot be rested by the effects of other cards.These effects make the affected Characters unable to perform any actions that require them to be rested, such as attacking or activating [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-011",
        "title": "EB02-011 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader has neither the {Fish-Man} nor the {East Blue} type, what happens with the effect \"up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a cost of 5 or less cannot be rested until the end of your opponent's next turn.\"?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, you will be unable to use the effect \"up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a cost of 5 or less cannot be rested until the end of your opponent's next turn.\" to prevent your opponent's Characters from being rested."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-012",
        "title": "EB02-012 Gaimon",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader has the effect \"This Leader is treated as a card with all card names, types, and attributes\", does this Character gain [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-013",
        "title": "EB02-013 Carrot",
        "question": "Q: [On Play] If I have 2 or less DON!! cards on my field, can I still play up to 1 [Zou] from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-015",
        "title": "EB02-015 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [On Play] effect but this Character is removed from my field during that turn, can I still set up to 1 of my DON!! cards as active at the end of that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-019",
        "title": "EB02-019 Roronoa Zoro",
        "question": "Q: I played this Character during my turn when my opponent had 2 Characters, but then another effect reduced the number of my opponent's Characters to 1. Can I still use this Character to attack my opponent's Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-022",
        "title": "EB02-022 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: Does the \"2 or less Characters\" in \"If you have 2 or less Characters with 5000 power or more,\" include this Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. You must have 2 or less Characters with 5000 power or more including \"EB02-022 Usopp\" in order to use this effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-022",
        "title": "EB02-022 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: I played this card when my opponent had 1 \"OP09-004 Shanks\" on their field and I had 2 Characters with a current power of 5000 or more on my field. In this case, how many Characters with 5000 power or more am I considered to have when activating this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, this card's power will be 4000, so you will be considered to have 2 Characters with 5000 power or more. You will therefore be able to use this [On Play] effect to play a Character card from your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-028",
        "title": "EB02-028 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have a type that includes \"Whitebeard Pirates\", can I still use this [On Play] effect to play up to 1 Character card with a cost of 2 from my hand rested?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-030",
        "title": "EB02-030 And That's When Somebody Makes Fun of Their Friend's Dream!!!!",
        "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, can I trash 1 card from my hand to prevent a Character I played after activating this Counter effect from being K.O.'d in battle?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-032",
        "title": "EB02-032 Iceburg",
        "question": "Q: [On Play] If I have 2 or less DON!! cards on my field, can I still play up to 1 [Galley-La Company] from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-033",
        "title": "EB02-033 Klabautermann",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader has the effect \"This Leader is treated as a card with all card names, types, and attributes\", does this Character gain [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-035",
        "title": "EB02-035 Sanji & Pudding",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Your Turn] effect if I have activated two [DON!! −1] effects during my turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This effect is activated when 2 or more DON!! cards are returned to your DON!! deck at the same time."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-035",
        "title": "EB02-035 Sanji & Pudding",
        "question": "Q: When I had 7 DON!! cards on my field and my opponent had 6 DON!! cards on theirs, I played \"ST18-005 Luffy-Tarou\" and used its \"[On Play] DON!! −1: Play up to 1 purple {Straw Hat Crew} type Character card with a cost of 5 or less from your hand.\" effect to play this card after returning 1 of my DON!! cards to my DON!! deck. In this case, can I use this card's [On Play] effect to draw 1 card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-047",
        "title": "EB02-047 Blueno",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [Activate: Main] effect to trash up to 1 Character card with a type including \"CP\" and a cost of 5 or less other than [Blueno], can I play the card I trashed?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-052",
        "title": "EB02-052 Enel",
        "question": "Q: If I have 2 or more Life cards, can I still use this [When Attacking] effect to give this Character +1000 power during this turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-055",
        "title": "EB02-055 Jinbe",
        "question": "Q: Can I use the [Trigger] effect \"If... you have 2 or less Life cards, play this card.\" to play this card if I have 2 or less Life cards including this card itself?",
        "answer": "A: No. You can play this card if you have 2 or less Life cards excluding this card."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-059",
        "title": "EB02-059 Without Your Help I Can't Become the King of the Pirates!!!!",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Counter] effect to play a [Sanji] with a cost of 6 or more or a [Sanji] with a color other than yellow?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-061",
        "title": "EB02-061 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: I played this Character during my turn when my opponent had 5 DON!! cards, but then another effect reduced the number of my opponent's DON!! cards to 4. Can this Character still attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-015",
        "title": "EB02-015 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: Will this [On Play] effect set 1 of my DON!! cards to active before or after my other [End of Your Turn] effects?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, this [On Play] effect will set 1 of your DON!! cards to active after all your other [End of Your Turn] effects have been activated and resolved."
    },
    {
        "id": "EB02-015",
        "title": "EB02-015 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: Can I set 1 of my DON!! cards to active using this [On Play] effect at the end of a turn in which I activated the [Activate: Main] effect of \"OP10-030 Smoker\", which includes the text \"you cannot set DON!! cards as active using Character effects during this turn.\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-003",
        "title": "OP10-003 Sugar",
        "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, I activated the 0 cost [Counter] effect of \"OP04-016 Bad Manners Kick Course\", but chose not to trash 1 card from my hand in response to \"you may trash 1 card from your hand\". Can I still use this Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect to add 1 DON!! card from my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-003",
        "title": "OP10-003 Sugar",
        "question": "Q: If I activate an Event's [Trigger] effect during my opponent's turn, can I use this Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect to add 1 DON!! card from my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-003",
        "title": "OP10-003 Sugar",
        "question": "Q: Does the [End of Your Turn] effect, \"if you have a {Donquixote Pirates} type Character with 6000 power or more\" activate before effects that increase power, such as \"gains +2000 power during this turn\", return to normal?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. In this case, the effect activates before the power returns to normal."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-008",
        "title": "OP10-008 Scotch",
        "question": "Q: I played [Rock] when I had 4 Characters that were neither [Rock] nor [Scotch], and activated its [On Play] effect. If I trash [Rock] in order to play [Scotch], can I use the [On Play] effect of [Scotch] to play another [Rock]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-010",
        "title": "OP10-010 Chadros.Higelyges (Brownbeard)",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is the only Character I have with 6000 power or more, and that 6000 power is a result of DON!! cards, can I still activate this Character's [When Attacking] effect to give this Character +1000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-016",
        "title": "OP10-016 Monet",
        "question": "Q: If I cannot use this [Activate: Main] effect to give 2 rested DON!! cards to my Leader or 1 of my Characters, can I still give 1 of my opponent's Characters −1000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-016",
        "title": "OP10-016 Monet",
        "question": "Q: If I cannot use this [Activate: Main] effect to give 1 of my opponent's Characters −1000 power, can I still give up to 2 rested DON!! cards to my Leader or 1 of my Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-017",
        "title": "OP10-017 Rock",
        "question": "Q: I played [Rock] when I had 4 Characters that were neither [Rock] nor [Scotch], and activated its [On Play] effect. If I trash [Rock] in order to play [Scotch], can I use the [On Play] effect of [Scotch] to play another [Rock]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-022",
        "title": "OP10-022 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: If the total cost of my Characters is 4 or less, can I return 1 of my Characters to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-022",
        "title": "OP10-022 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: What happens if I use this [Activate: Main] effect to reveal 1 card from the top of my Life cards, and that card is not a {Supernovas} type Character card?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, return the revealed card to the top of your Life cards face-down."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-026",
        "title": "OP10-026 Kin'emon",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to place 2 [Kin'emon] cards from my trash at the bottom of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. In order to play 1 [Kin'emon] with a cost of 6 from your hand you must place this [Kin'emon] from your field and 1 [Kin'emon] with 0 power from your trash at the bottom of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-027",
        "title": "OP10-027 Kin'emon",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to place 2 [Kin'emon] cards from my trash at the bottom of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. In order to play 1 [Kin'emon] with a cost of 6 from your hand you must place this [Kin'emon] from your field and 1 [Kin'emon] with 1000 power from your trash at the bottom of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-030",
        "title": "OP10-030 Smoker",
        "question": "Q: After using this [Activate: Main] effect, can I use the effect on the Leader card \"OP10-001 Smoker\" to set 2 of my DON!! cards as active on the same turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-030",
        "title": "OP10-030 Smoker",
        "question": "Q: After using this [Activate: Main] effect, can I use the effect on \"OP07-021 Urouge\" to set 1 of my DON!! cards as active at the end of the turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-032",
        "title": "OP10-032 Tashigi",
        "question": "Q: If I have a green Character that would be removed from the field by my opponent's effect while this Character is rested, can I still use this Character's effect to rest this Character instead?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-032",
        "title": "OP10-032 Tashigi",
        "question": "Q: If both this Character and a green Character other than this Character are K.O.'d at the same time while this Character is active, can I still use this effect to rest this Character instead?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, your other green Character will not be K.O.'d, but [Tashigi] will still be K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-041",
        "title": "OP10-041 Radio Knife",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to rest 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 5 or less, then K.O. that same Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-042",
        "title": "OP10-042 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: If one of my {Dressrosa} type Characters has an [On K.O.] effect and is K.O.'d during my opponent's turn, does this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect activate first, or does that Character's [On K.O.] effect activate first?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, you can activate the card's [On K.O.] effect and this Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect in any order you choose."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-042",
        "title": "OP10-042 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: If one of my {Dressrosa} type Characters is K.O.'d by my opponent's attack, can I use this [Opponent's Turn] effect to draw 1 card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-049",
        "title": "OP10-049 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: If this Character and another of my Characters with a base cost of 7 or less are K.O.'d at the same time by my opponent's effect, can I use this effect to return this Character to my hand instead?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-057",
        "title": "OP10-057 Leo",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [On Play] effect when my Leader was [Usopp] to look at 5 cards from the top of my deck, but only added 0 or 1 {Dressrosa} type cards other than [Leo] to my hand. Do I still need to trash 1 card from my hand due to this effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. Regardless of the number of cards you added to your hand, you must still place the rest at the bottom of your deck in any order and trash 1 card from your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-058",
        "title": "OP10-058 Rebecca",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [On Play] effect to reveal only 1 {Dressrosa} type Character card with a cost of 4, will that Character be played rested?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will be played set as active."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-058",
        "title": "OP10-058 Rebecca",
        "question": "Q: I used this [On Play] effect to play [Character A] as active and [Character B] rested. Can I choose the order in which to activate [Character A] and [Character B]'s [On Play] effects?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the player who played this Character can activate the effects in any order they choose."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-058",
        "title": "OP10-058 Rebecca",
        "question": "Q: I played this Character, causing my number of Characters to become 4 including this Character, then used this [On Play] effect to play [Character A] as active; I then trashed [Character A] and played [Character B] rested. Can I still activate the [On Play] effect of [Character A]?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-067",
        "title": "OP10-067 Senor Pink",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [On Play] effect but didn't add 1 Event to my hand, can I still set 1 of my DON!! cards as active?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-069",
        "title": "OP10-069 Fighting Fish",
        "question": "Q: I attacked with this Character while it was given 1 DON!! card, but that DON!! card was removed when using the DON!! −1 part of this card's [When Attacking] effect, causing the number of DON!! cards given to this Character to become 0. Can I still K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 1 or less?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-070",
        "title": "OP10-070 Trebol",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [On Play] effect when I had \"EB01-061 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)\" on my field. If the [When Attacking] effect of \"EB01-061 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)\" causes its base power to become 2000 or more during the same turn, can it be K.O.'d by my opponent's effects?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-071",
        "title": "OP10-071 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: My opponent attacked me while I have 2 of this Character on my field, 1 active DON!! card on my field, and 2 cards in my DON!! deck. Can I activate this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect twice to add 2 DON!! cards from my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. After activating the first card's [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect to add a DON!! card, you can then rest that DON!! card to activate the second card's [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-087",
        "title": "OP10-087 Tony Tony.Chopper",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has 4 or less cards in their hand, can I still use this [Activate: Main] effect to trash 2 cards from the top of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-091",
        "title": "OP10-091 Brook",
        "question": "Q: When using this [Activate: Main] effect, can I trash 2 cards from the top of my deck without K.O.'ing an opponent's character with a cost of 1 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-095",
        "title": "OP10-095 Roronoa Zoro",
        "question": "Q: Using this [On Play] effect, can I trash 2 cards from the top of my deck without having to K.O. my opponent's Character with a cost of 4 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-097",
        "title": "OP10-097 Gum-Gum Rhino Schneider",
        "question": "Q: I have 9 cards in my trash and activate this [Main] effect. Does the selected Character still gain [Banish]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-098",
        "title": "OP10-098 Liberation",
        "question": "Q: Can I negate the effect \"Under the rules of this game, you may have any number of this card in your deck.\" using this card's [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, even if your opponent has 5 or more cards in their deck that are the same as the card that had its effect negated, it will have no effect on the match."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-098",
        "title": "OP10-098 Liberation",
        "question": "Q: I used this card's [Trigger] effect to negate the effect of my opponent's Leader for one turn when my opponent's Leader was \"OP03-040 Nami\". What happens if my opponent's deck is reduced to 0 during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, your opponent will lose the game."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-098",
        "title": "OP10-098 Liberation",
        "question": "Q: If a Character is K.O.'d while affected by this card's [Trigger] effect, can that Character's [On K.O.] effect still activate?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-098",
        "title": "OP10-098 Liberation",
        "question": "Q: Can the [Trigger] effect of this card negate effects on the chosen card that were granted by other cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-099",
        "title": "OP10-099 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid",
        "question": "Q: Using this [End of Your Turn] effect, can one of my active {Supernovas} type Characters with a cost of 3 to 8 gain [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. A Character that is already set as active can still gain [Blocker] from this effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-100",
        "title": "OP10-100 Inazuma",
        "question": "Q: Does the [Trigger] effect, \"If your Leader has the {Revolutionary Army} type and you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards, play this card.\" mean that I can play this card if my and my opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards, including this card itself?",
        "answer": "A: No. In order to play this card using the [Trigger] effect, the total Life cards of you and your opponent, excluding this card, must be 5 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-102",
        "title": "OP10-102 Emporio.Ivankov",
        "question": "Q: When I have 0 Life cards, can I still use this [Activate: Main] effect to have 3 of my {Revolutionary Army} type Characters gain +1000 power during this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-110",
        "title": "OP10-110 Heat & Wire",
        "question": "Q: Does the [Trigger] effect, \"If you have 2 or less Life cards\" mean that I can play this card if I have 2 or less Life cards, including this card itself?",
        "answer": "A: No. In order to play this card using the [Trigger] effect, your total Life cards, excluding this card, must be 2 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-116",
        "title": "OP10-116 Damned Punk",
        "question": "Q: Using this [Main] effect, if there are no Life cards to look at, can I still K.O. up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a cost of 5 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-116",
        "title": "OP10-116 Damned Punk",
        "question": "Q: Using this [Main] effect, can I look at a card that is face-up in my or my opponent's Life cards, and still K.O. up to 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 5 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, after looking at the face-up card, it will remain face-up once you place it at the top or bottom of the Life cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-118",
        "title": "OP10-118 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: When this Character is K.O.'d by an opponent's effect for the first time in a turn, can I choose to allow this Character to be K.O.'d?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-118",
        "title": "OP10-118 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has 4 or less cards in their hand, can I still use this [When Attacking] effect to place 3 cards from my trash at the bottom of my deck in any order?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, after using the [When Attacking] effect and placing 3 cards from your trash at the bottom of your deck in any order, nothing else occurs."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-119",
        "title": "OP10-119 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have the {Supernovas} type, can I still use this [On Play] effect to add 1 {Supernovas} type Character card from my hand to my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-042",
        "title": "OP10-042 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, my \"OP10-090 Franky\" was K.O.'d, and I activated its [On K.O.] effect to play \"OP04-092 Rebecca\" before the activation of this Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect. In this case, which effect activates first: this Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect or the [On Play] effect of \"OP04-092 Rebecca\"?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, this Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect will always activate before the [On Play] effect of a Character played using the [On K.O.] effect of \"OP10-090 Franky\"."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-042",
        "title": "OP10-042 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: I have \"OP04-089 Bartolomeo\", a card with a base cost of 3, on my field, which currently has a cost of 4 due to this Leader's effect. During my opponent's turn, my opponent uses the [On Play] effect of \"OP02-106 Tsuru\" to give Bartolomeo −2 cost. What would Bartolomeo's cost become in this case?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, Bartolomeo's cost would become 2.Usopp's effect is a permanent effect, meaning it is processed first: this raises Bartolomeo's cost from 3 to 4. Tsuru's [On Play] effect, which is an auto effect, is processed after that, dropping Bartolomeo's cost from 4 to 2."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-042",
        "title": "OP10-042 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: I have \"OP04-089 Bartolomeo\", a card with a base cost of 3, on my field, which currently has a cost of 4 due to this Leader's effect. During my opponent's turn, my opponent uses the [On Play] effect of \"OP07-080 Kaku\" to give Bartolomeo −3 cost. What would Bartolomeo's cost become in this case?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, Bartolomeo's cost would become 0.Usopp's effect is a permanent effect, meaning it is processed first: this raises Bartolomeo's cost from 3 to 4. Kaku's [On Play] effect, which is an auto effect, is processed after that, dropping Bartolomeo's cost from 4 to 1. As this means that Bartolomeo's cost is now 1 or less, Usopp's effect would no longer apply to it; it would lose the +1 cost from Usopp's effect, so its cost would become 0."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-042",
        "title": "OP10-042 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: I have \"OP04-089 Bartolomeo\", a card with a base cost of 3, on my field, and it currently has a cost of 4 due to this Leader's effect. During my opponent's turn, my opponent gives a DON!! card to \"OP03-078 Issho\", then uses Issho's [Your Turn] effect to give Bartolomeo −3 cost. What would Bartolomeo's cost become in this case?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, Bartolomeo's cost would become 0.As the effects of the turn player's cards' take priority, Issho's permanent effect will be processed first, dropping Bartolomeo's cost from 3 to 0. The effects of the non-turn player's cards will then be processed, but Usopp's permanent effect will not be applied to give Bartolomeo +1 cost, meaning that its cost will remain 0."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-098",
        "title": "OP10-098 Liberation",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to K.O. my opponent's character with a base cost of 7 or more if its cost has been lowered by another effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This effect can K.O. up to 1 each of the following: up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a base cost of 6 or less, and up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a base cost of 4 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-098",
        "title": "OP10-098 Liberation",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to K.O. one of my opponent's Characters with a base cost of 6 or less, and another of my opponent's Characters with a current cost of 4 or less but a base cost of 5 or higher?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This effect can K.O. up to 1 each of the following: up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a base cost of 6 or less, and up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a base cost of 4 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP10-112",
        "title": "OP10-112 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid",
        "question": "Q: On my opponent's previous turn, this card was selected as the target of the [Activate: Main] effect of my opponent's \"OP09-093 Marshal.D.Teach\", causing its effects to be negated until the end of this turn. Can I still activate this [End of Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. During the End Phase, [End of Your Turn] effects are activated first, followed by effects that last \"until the end of your/your opponent's next turn\".Although the effect of \"Marshall.D.Teach\" also expires at this point, it will be too late to activate the [End of Your Turn] effect of this card, as its activation window has already passed."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-001",
        "title": "OP09-001 Shanks",
        "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, can I choose not to activate this [Once Per Turn] effect when my opponent first attacks, and instead activate it the next time they attack?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-001",
        "title": "OP09-001 Shanks",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this \"when your opponent attacks\" effect regardless of whether my opponent is attacking with their Leader or attacking with a Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Provided it's only once per turn, you can activate this effect regardless of whether your opponent is attacking with their Leader or attacking with a Character."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-009",
        "title": "OP09-009 Benn.Beckman",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate the [On K.O.] effect of a Character that has been trashed as a result of this card's [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-014",
        "title": "OP09-014 Limejuice",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent's Character with 4000 power or less that has been selected as the target of this [On Play] effect comes to have 5000 or more power as the result of another effect during the same turn, can that Character's [Blocker] be activated?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-018",
        "title": "OP09-018 Get Out of Here!",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to K.O. 1 Character with 4000 power or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-018",
        "title": "OP09-018 Get Out of Here!",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to K.O. 1 Character with −2000 power and 1 Character with 6000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-022",
        "title": "OP09-022 Lim",
        "question": "Q: When playing a Character rested based on this \"Your Character cards are played rested.\" effect, can I activate effects such as \"If a Character is rested by your effect\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-030",
        "title": "OP09-030 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to return this Character itself to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, you can still play up to 1 {ODYSSEY} type Character card with a cost of 3 or less other than [Trafalgar Law] from your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-031",
        "title": "OP09-031 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: If I have no other Characters on my field other than 2 of this Character rested, can I use this [End of Your Turn] effect to set both Characters as active?",
        "answer": "A: No, you can only set 1 of them as active."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-032",
        "title": "OP09-032 Donquixote Rosinante",
        "question": "Q: If I set this Character as active using this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect, can I activate its [Blocker] effect in response to the same attack?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-032",
        "title": "OP09-032 Donquixote Rosinante",
        "question": "Q: My opponent's Character attacked and its [When Attacking] effect caused this Character to become rested. At this time, can I use this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect to set this Character as active?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-037",
        "title": "OP09-037 Lim",
        "question": "Q: If I have no other Characters on my field other than 3 of this Character rested, can I use this [End of Your Turn] effect to set all 3 Characters as active?",
        "answer": "A: No, you can only set 1 of them as active."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-041",
        "title": "OP09-041 Soul Franky Swing Arm Boxing Solid",
        "question": "Q: Can the [Blocker] effect of a Character that has been set as active using the [Counter] effect of this card be activated during the same battle?",
        "answer": "A: No, the Block Step of the battle would have already ended, so you would not be able to activate a [Blocker] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-052",
        "title": "OP09-052 Marco",
        "question": "Q: When do I \"trash 1 card from my hand\" as part of this [Opponent's Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: You trash 1 cards from your hand when this Character is K.O.'d by your opponent's effect during your opponent's turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-052",
        "title": "OP09-052 Marco",
        "question": "Q: When this Character is K.O.'d by an effect during my opponent's turn, can I choose not to trash 1 card from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, you will be unable to use this Character's [Opponent's Turn] effect to play this Character."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-058",
        "title": "OP09-058 Special Muggy Ball",
        "question": "Q: Which player chooses the Character to be returned to the owner's hand as part of this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, the opponent of the player who used this card will choose 1 Character with a cost of 6 or less from their field and return that Character to their hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-061",
        "title": "OP09-061 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If I activate a [DON!! −1] effect twice during my turn, can I still activate this [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This effect only activates when 2 or more DON!! cards are returned to your DON!! deck at the same time."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-061",
        "title": "OP09-061 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: I activated the [Activate: Main] effect of \"OP08-074 Black Maria\" and returned 2 or more DON!! cards to my deck at the end of a turn in which I had not yet activated this [Your Turn] effect. Can I still activate this [Your Turn] effect at this time?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-081",
        "title": "OP09-081 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: My opponent took damage during the same turn in which I used this [Activate: Main] effect, and their Life card was \"OP08-106 Nami\". What happens to the \"[Trigger] Activate this card's [On Play] effect.\" on \"OP08-106 Nami\" in this case?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, your opponent can choose to activate the [Trigger] effect on \"OP08-106 Nami\", but because [On Play] effects are negated, nothing will happen and [OP08-106 Nami] will be trashed."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-081",
        "title": "OP09-081 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: Can I use cards with [On Play] effects in a deck with this Leader?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can include cards with [On Play] effects in the same deck as this Leader. However, all [On Play] effects will be negated due to this Leader's effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-081",
        "title": "OP09-081 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent plays a Character with an [On Play]/[When Attacking] effect on the turn after I used this [Activate: Main] effect, will my opponent be able to activate that Character's [On Play]/[When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, they will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-081",
        "title": "OP09-081 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent attacks with a Character with an [On Play]/[When Attacking] effect on the turn after I used this [Activate: Main] effect, will my opponent be able to activate that Character's [On Play]/[When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-081",
        "title": "OP09-081 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: I used this [Activate: Main] effect when my opponent's Leader was \"PRB01-001 Sanji\", and my opponent played a Character with an [On Play] effect the next turn. Can my opponent use the [Activate: Main] effect on \"PRB01-001 Sanji\" on that Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, they cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-081",
        "title": "OP09-081 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: While [On Play] effects are being negated by this card, are my Characters with only [On Play] effects treated as Characters with no base effects?",
        "answer": "A: No, they are not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-086",
        "title": "OP09-086 Jesus Burgess",
        "question": "Q: This Character was attacked while rested when I had 7 cards in my trash, and I trashed 1 +1000 Counter from my hand. In this case, will this Character gain power based on its effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-089",
        "title": "OP09-089 Stronger",
        "question": "Q: After drawing 1 card with this [Activate: Main] effect, can I look at the card before choosing which of my opponent's Characters to give -2 cost to?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-093",
        "title": "OP09-093 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: Can I negate the effect \"Under the rules of this game, you may have any number of this card in your deck.\" using this card's effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, even if your opponent has 5 or more cards in their deck that are the same as the card that had its effect negated, it will have no effect on the match."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-093",
        "title": "OP09-093 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: I used this card's effect to negate the effect of my opponent's Leader for one turn when my opponent's Leader was \"OP03-040 Nami\". What happens if my opponent's deck is reduced to 0 during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, your opponent will lose the game."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-093",
        "title": "OP09-093 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: If a Character that had its effect negated by this card's effect is K.O.'d, can that Character's [On K.O.] effect be activated?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-093",
        "title": "OP09-093 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: If the card I choose for this card's effect is also receiving effects from another card, will this card's effect negate those effects as well?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-093",
        "title": "OP09-093 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: How long will the Character chosen as the target for this [Activate: Main] effect be unable to attack?",
        "answer": "A: It will be unable to attack until the end of your opponent's next turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-097",
        "title": "OP09-097 Black Vortex",
        "question": "Q: Can I negate the effect \"Under the rules of this game, you may have any number of this card in your deck.\" using this card's effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, even if your opponent has 5 or more cards in their deck that are the same as the card that had its effect negated, it will have no effect on the match."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-097",
        "title": "OP09-097 Black Vortex",
        "question": "Q: I used this card's effect to negate the effect of my opponent's Leader for one turn when my opponent's Leader was \"OP03-040 Nami\". What happens if my opponent's deck is reduced to 0 during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, your opponent will lose the game."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-097",
        "title": "OP09-097 Black Vortex",
        "question": "Q: If a Character that had its effect negated by this card's effect is K.O.'d, can that Character's [On K.O.] effect be activated?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-097",
        "title": "OP09-097 Black Vortex",
        "question": "Q: If the card I choose for this card's effect is also receiving effects from another card, will this card's effect negate those effects as well?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-098",
        "title": "OP09-098 Black Hole",
        "question": "Q: Can I negate the effect \"Under the rules of this game, you may have any number of this card in your deck.\" using this card's effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, even if your opponent has 5 or more cards in their deck that are the same as the card that had its effect negated, it will have no effect on the match."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-098",
        "title": "OP09-098 Black Hole",
        "question": "Q: I used this card's [Trigger] effect to negate the effect of my opponent's Leader for one turn when my opponent's Leader was \"OP03-040 Nami\". What happens if my opponent's deck is reduced to 0 during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, your opponent will lose the game."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-098",
        "title": "OP09-098 Black Hole",
        "question": "Q: If a Character that had its effect negated by this card's effect is K.O.'d, can that Character's [On K.O.] effect be activated?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-098",
        "title": "OP09-098 Black Hole",
        "question": "Q: If the card I choose for this card's effect is also receiving effects from another card, will this card's effect negate those effects as well?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-098",
        "title": "OP09-098 Black Hole",
        "question": "Q: I used the [Main] effect on \"OP07-096 Tempest Kick\" to give my opponent's \"OP08-084 Jack\" −3 cost. Can I K.O. \"OP08-084 Jack\" using this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-100",
        "title": "OP09-100 Karasu",
        "question": "Q: Does the number of Life cards in the [Trigger] effect \"If your Leader has the {Revolutionary Army} type and you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards, play this card.\" include this card?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not. You can play this card when you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards excluding this card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-101",
        "title": "OP09-101 Kuzan",
        "question": "Q: Can I still activate this [On Play] effect even if it is not possible to place 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 3 or less in their Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-103",
        "title": "OP09-103 Koala",
        "question": "Q: When activating this [On Play] effect, can I still draw 1 card even if I choose to play 0 {Revolutionary Army} type Character cards with a cost of 4 or less from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-105",
        "title": "OP09-105 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: If I have 1 or less cards in my hand, can I still use this [Trigger] effect to add up to 1 card from the top of my deck to the top of my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-104",
        "title": "OP09-104 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: When activating this [On Play] effect, if I do not add a {Revolutionary Army} type Character card from my hand to my Life cards, do I still add 1 card from the top or bottom of my Life cards to my hand if I have 2 or more Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you do."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-108",
        "title": "OP09-108 Bartholomew Kuma",
        "question": "Q: Does the number of Life cards specified in the [Trigger] effect \"If your Leader has the {Revolutionary Army} type and you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards, play this card.\" include this card?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not. You can play this card when you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards excluding this card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-112",
        "title": "OP09-112 Belo Betty",
        "question": "Q: Does the number of Life cards specified in the [Trigger] effect \"If your Leader has the {Revolutionary Army} type and you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards, play this card.\" include this card?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not. You can play this card when you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards excluding this card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-114",
        "title": "OP09-114 Lindbergh",
        "question": "Q: Does the number of Life cards specified in the [Trigger] effect \"If you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards, play this card.\" include this card?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not. You can play this card when you and your opponent have a total of 5 or less Life cards excluding this card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-118",
        "title": "OP09-118 Gol.D.Roger",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent activates a [Blocker] effect in response to an attack from a card other than this Character when this Character is on my field, and either me or my opponent has 0 Life cards, will I win the game?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you win the game."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-118",
        "title": "OP09-118 Gol.D.Roger",
        "question": "Q: I attacked with this Character when both me and my opponent had 1 Life card left, and my opponent blocked my attack with \"ST09-007 Shinobu\". At this time, if my opponent activates the [On Block] effect of \"ST09-007 Shinobu\" and their Life cards are reduced to 0, will I win the game based on this Character's effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you will not win the game."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-068",
        "title": "OP09-068 Tony Tony.Chopper",
        "question": "Q: Can I use another card's \"negate the effect of...\" effect to negate the [Blocker] gained from this [End of Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP09-084",
        "title": "OP09-084 Catarina Devon",
        "question": "Q: Can I use another card's \"negate the effect of...\" effect to negate the [Blocker] gained from this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-001",
        "title": "OP08-001 Tony Tony.Chopper",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give a Character more than 2 DON!! cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-006",
        "title": "OP08-006 Chessmarimo",
        "question": "Q: If I have another [Chessmarimo] card in my trash, does this Character gain +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not. This Character gains +2000 power if you have at least one card with the name [Kuromarimo] and at least one card with the name [Chess] in your trash."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-014",
        "title": "OP08-014 Wapol",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to give this Character +2000 power even if my opponent has no Characters on their field?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-019",
        "title": "OP08-019 Munch-Munch Mutation",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main]/[Counter] effect to give one of my Characters +3000 power even if my opponent has no Characters on their field?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-036",
        "title": "OP08-036 Electrical Luna",
        "question": "Q: If one of my opponent's rested Characters with a cost of 7 or less is active at the time of activating this [Main] effect but becomes rested due to another effect, does it not become active in my opponent's next Refresh Phase?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does become active."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-038",
        "title": "OP08-038 We Would Never Sell a Comrade to an Enemy!!!",
        "question": "Q: If I play a Character after this [Main] effect is activated, will that Characterbe unable to be K.O.'d by my opponent's effects until the end of my opponent's next turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, it can be K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-039",
        "title": "OP08-039 Zou",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [End of Your Turn] effect to set 1 of my {Minks} type Characters as active even if my Leader does not have the {Minks} type?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-040",
        "title": "OP08-040 Atmos",
        "question": "Q: What does \"You may reveal 2 cards with a type including \"Whitebeard Pirates\" from your hand:\" mean?",
        "answer": "A: It means that you reveal 2 cards with a type including \"Whitebeard Pirates\" from your hand to your opponent, before returning them to their previous state."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-043",
        "title": "OP08-043 Edward.Newgate",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent plays a Character with [Rush] on their next turn after this [On Play] effect is activated, will that Character be able to attack?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-043",
        "title": "OP08-043 Edward.Newgate",
        "question": "Q: I had 3 or more Life cards when this [Main] effect was activated, but during my opponent's turn my number of Life cards dropped to 2 or less. In this case, does this [On Play] effect mean that my opponent's Characters will be unable to attack unless they trash 2 cards from their hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, your opponent's Characters will be able to attack without them trashing 2 cards from their hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-044",
        "title": "OP08-044 Kingdew",
        "question": "Q: What does \"You may reveal 2 cards with a type including \"Whitebeard Pirates\" from your hand:\" mean?",
        "answer": "A: It means that you reveal 2 cards with a type including \"Whitebeard Pirates\" from your hand to your opponent, before returning them to their previous state."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-045",
        "title": "OP08-045 Thatch",
        "question": "Q: If this card would be K.O.'d and I trash it to draw 1 card instead, does that activate the \"When a Character is K.O.'d\" effect of another card?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-046",
        "title": "OP08-046 Shakuyaku",
        "question": "Q: If this Character has already become rested due to another effect, can I still use this [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-055",
        "title": "OP08-055 Phoenix Brand",
        "question": "Q: What does \"You may reveal 2 cards with a type including \"Whitebeard Pirates\" from your hand:\" mean?",
        "answer": "A: It means that you reveal 2 cards with a type including \"Whitebeard Pirates\" from your hand to your opponent, before returning them to their previous state."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-058",
        "title": "OP08-058 Charlotte Pudding",
        "question": "Q: If 1 or more of the 2 cards taken from the top of my Life cards are already turned face-up, can I still use this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-060",
        "title": "OP08-060 King",
        "question": "Q: If this Character gains [Rush] from this [On Play] effect due to my opponent having 5 or more DON!! cards on their field, and the number of DON!! cards on my opponent's field subsequently drops to 4 or less, will this Character still be able to attack on that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-063",
        "title": "OP08-063 Charlotte Katakuri",
        "question": "Q: If the card chosen from the top of my Life cards is already face-down, can I still use this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-074",
        "title": "OP08-074 Black Maria",
        "question": "Q: If I return DON!! cards from my field to my DON!! deck at the end of my turn based on this [Activate: Main] effect, can I use the \"When a DON!! card on your field is returned to your DON!! deck,\" effect of another of my cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-079",
        "title": "OP08-079 Kaido",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect and trash 1 card from my hand on any turn after the turn this Character was played?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, nothing happens after you trash 1 card from your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-082",
        "title": "OP08-082 Sasaki",
        "question": "Q: Is the \"Rest 1 of your DON!! cards\" part in this [Activate: Main] effect equivalent to the \"➀ (You may rest the specified number of DON!! cards in your cost area.)\" effect of other cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, both refer to activation costs that can be paid by resting one of the active DON!! cards in your cost area."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-084",
        "title": "OP08-084 Jack",
        "question": "Q: Is the cost of this Character card 11 when it is in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, the cost of this card when in your hand is 7. The \"This Character gains +4 cost.\" effect only applies when this Character is on your field."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-098",
        "title": "OP08-098 Kalgara",
        "question": "Q: When I have 0 or less Life cards remaining, can I use this [When Attacking] effect to \"Play up to 1 {Shandian Warrior} type Character card from my hand with a cost equal to or less than the number of DON!! cards on my field.\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-105",
        "title": "OP08-105 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: When one of my opponent's Life cards is moved to my opponent's hand or trashed based on the effect of one of my opponent's cards, can I use this [Your Turn] effect to draw 2 cards and trash 1 card from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-114",
        "title": "OP08-114 S-Hawk",
        "question": "Q: If I have less Life cards than my opponent, does this Character still gain +2000 power from this [DON!! x1] effect even when not in battle with a <Slash> attribute card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does still gain +2000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-118",
        "title": "OP08-118 Silvers Rayleigh",
        "question": "Q: When using this [On Play] effect, can the Character selected to be given −3000 power, the Character selected to be given −2000 power, and the Character selected to be K.O.'d all be different Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-105",
        "title": "OP08-105 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this \"When a card is removed from your opponent's Life cards\" effect when looking at my opponent's Life cards, when my opponent reveals their Life cards, or when my opponent changes the order of their Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can only use this effect when one of your opponent's Life cards is moved from their Life area to another area."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP08-105",
        "title": "OP08-105 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: During my turn, my opponent used an effect to add 1 Life card to their hand, then added a card to the top of their Life cards. Can I still use this [Your Turn] effect to draw 2 cards and trash 1 card from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-001",
        "title": "OP07-001 Monkey.D.Dragon",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to take 2 DON!! cards currently given to my Character(s) and give 1 each to 2 of my other Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-001",
        "title": "OP07-001 Monkey.D.Dragon",
        "question": "Q: If 1 of my Characters already has 2 DON!! cards given to it, can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give those 2 DON!! cards to that Character again?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-001",
        "title": "OP07-001 Monkey.D.Dragon",
        "question": "Q: If 2 of my Characters have 1 DON!! card each given to them, can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give these 2 DON!! cards to 1 of my other Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-002",
        "title": "OP07-002 Ain",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader attacks my opponent's Character that has a power of 0 due to this Character's [On Play] effect, and my opponent uses [Counter +1000] on that Character, does that Character's power continue to be 0?",
        "answer": "A: No, the Character's power will be 1000 during the battle."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-002",
        "title": "OP07-002 Ain",
        "question": "Q: During my turn, my opponent's \"OP05-012 Hack\" with a base power of 5000 is given +2000 power by the [Counter] effect of \"OP07-018 KEEP OUT\", making its power 7000 until the end of my opponent's next turn. If I use this [On Play] effect of my Character on that \"Hack\" card, will that \"Hack\" card's power be 0 during my current turn, and then 7000 during my opponent's turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, in this case, it's power will become 7000."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-014",
        "title": "OP07-014 Moda",
        "question": "Q: When I play this 1 card on my turn, can I use this card's [On Play] effect to give my 1 \"Portgas.D.Ace\" +2000 power and the [Your Turn] effect to give it a further +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This card's effect is an [On Play] effect that only activates during your turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-017",
        "title": "OP07-017 Dragon Breath",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to K.O. my opponent's Character with 3000 power or less even if my opponent has no Stage with a cost of 1 or less on their field?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-019",
        "title": "OP07-019 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, can I choose not to use this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect the first time my opponent attacks, and then use this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect the second time my opponent attacks?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-024",
        "title": "OP07-024 Koala",
        "question": "Q: When my opponent attacks, can the Character who gains [Blocker] according to this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect activate that [Blocker] against that attack?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-026",
        "title": "OP07-026 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose 1 of my opponent's active DON!! cards according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-026",
        "title": "OP07-026 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose 1 DON!! card currently given to my opponent's Character according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-029",
        "title": "OP07-029 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: If there are no active Characters on my opponent's field, can I still use this [Once Per Turn] effect to prevent this Character from being removed from the field?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-031",
        "title": "OP07-031 Bartolomeo",
        "question": "Q: During my turn, if I activate an effect such as \"[Activate: Main] Rest this Character:\" and rest my Character, can I activate this Character's [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-038",
        "title": "OP07-038 Boa Hancock",
        "question": "Q: During my turn, can I choose not to activate this [Your Turn] effect to draw 1 card the first time a Character is removed from the field by my effect, but instead choose to activate this [Your Turn] effect to draw 1 card the next time a Character is removed from the field by my effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-042",
        "title": "OP07-042 Gecko Moria",
        "question": "Q: If the only Character I have is \"Gecko Moria\", can I use this [Once Per Turn] effect to prevent this Character from being removed from the field?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-043",
        "title": "OP07-043 Salome",
        "question": "Q: When I play this 1 card on my turn, can I use this card's [On Play] effect to give my \"Boa Hancock\" +2000 power and the [Your Turn] effect to give it a further +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This card's effect is an [On Play] effect that only activates during your turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-059",
        "title": "OP07-059 Foxy",
        "question": "Q: Can I select my opponent's rested Leader and 1 of their rested Characters, for a total of 2 cards, according to this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-059",
        "title": "OP07-059 Foxy",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent's Leader is active, can I select 1 of my opponent's rested Characters according to this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-064",
        "title": "OP07-064 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: If I activate the [Activate: Main] effect of my \"ST10-001 Trafalgar Law\" and the number of DON!! Cards on my field is at least 2 less than the number on my opponent's field, can I use that [Activate: Main] effect to play this \"OP07-064 Sanji\" from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-085",
        "title": "OP07-085 Stussy",
        "question": "Q: If I have 0 Characters, can I play this Character and use this [On Play] effect to trash this Character and K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-088",
        "title": "OP07-088 Hattori",
        "question": "Q: When I play this 1 card on my turn, can I use this card's [On Play] effect to give my \"Rob Lucci\" +2000 power and the [Your Turn] effect to give it a further +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This card's effect is an [On Play] effect that only activates during your turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-090",
        "title": "OP07-090 Morgans",
        "question": "Q: Should my opponent reveal the card they draw according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, the card should not be revealed."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-091",
        "title": "OP07-091 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If I put 5 Character cards with a cost of 4 or more from my trash at the bottom of my deck according to this [When Attacking] effect, what happens to this Character's power?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, this Character's power becomes +1000 according to this [When Attacking] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-093",
        "title": "OP07-093 Rob Lucci",
        "question": "Q: When I place up to 1 card from my opponent's trash at the bottom of their deck according to this [On Play] effect, which player chooses which card is placed at the bottom of the deck?",
        "answer": "A: The player using this card chooses, and that card is placed at the bottom of the owner's deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-094",
        "title": "OP07-094 Shave",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Counter] effect when I had 9 cards in my trash. At this time, can I return up to 1 of my Characters with a type including \"CP\" to the owner's hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-095",
        "title": "OP07-095 Iron Body",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Counter] effect when I had 9 cards in my trash. At this time, can I give a total of +6000 power to 1 of my Leader or Character cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-096",
        "title": "OP07-096 Tempest Kick",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Main] effect when I had 9 cards in my trash. At this time, can I give up to 1 of my opponent's Characters −3 cost during this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-097",
        "title": "OP07-097 Vegapunk",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to play an {Egghead} type Event card with a cost of 5 or less from my hand onto my field or activate it?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-107",
        "title": "OP07-107 Franky",
        "question": "Q: Can I draw a card according to this [Trigger] effect if I have 2 or more Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you will draw 1 card according to this [Trigger] effect and trash this card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-111",
        "title": "OP07-111 Lilith",
        "question": "Q: Do I need to reveal the card added to my hand according to this [On Play] effect to my opponent?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you reveal that you have 1 {Egghead} type card to your opponent and add it to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-119",
        "title": "OP07-119 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: If I play this Character when I have 2 or less Life cards, and I do not add a card from my deck to my Life cards according to this [On Play] effect, can this Character gain [Rush] during this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-019",
        "title": "OP07-019 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: My opponent attacked with \"OP01-060 Donquixote Doflamingo\", then used its [When Attacking] effect to play \"OP07-045 Jinbe\". If my opponent then plays a Character using Jinbe's [On Play] effect, can I use this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect to rest that Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot.First, Jinbe is played with Donquixote Doflamingo's \"When Attacking\" effect, followed by the activation of this card's \"On Your Opponent's Attack\" effect. Then, Jinbe's \"On Play\" effect activates, allowing your opponent to play a Character from their hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP07-029",
        "title": "OP07-029 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is removed from the field by my opponent's effect, can I use this [Once Per Turn] effect to rest my opponent's Character even if it cannot be rested?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-002",
        "title": "OP06-002 Inazuma",
        "question": "Q: If I use this Character with 7000 power to attack, and this Character's power is reduced to 6000 or less by the [Counter] effect of my opponent's Event, what happens to this Character's [Banish]?",
        "answer": "A: The battle is processed without your Character having [Banish]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-006",
        "title": "OP06-006 Saga",
        "question": "Q: If, after activating this [When Attacking] effect, this Character leaves the field during that turn, do I still trash 1 of my {FILM} type Characters at the end of that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. If you have other {FILM} type Characters on your field, you must trash 1 of them."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-009",
        "title": "OP06-009 Shuraiya",
        "question": "Q: If this Character has 1 DON!! card given to it and attacks my opponent's Leader with 5000 power, does this Character's power become 6000 according to this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does.(Please see the official website for this card's updated text.)"
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-009",
        "title": "OP06-009 Shuraiya",
        "question": "Q: My opponent's Leader attacked with DON!! cards given to it and 8000 power. I activated this Character's [Blocker] and this Character's power became 8000 according to its [On Block] effect. Can I then use a Counter to further increase this Character's power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can.(Please see the official website for this card's updated text.)"
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-009",
        "title": "OP06-009 Shuraiya",
        "question": "Q: I activated this card's [When Attacking] effect on attacking with this Character. My opponent's Leader had 5000 power at the time, but my opponent then used a Counter to raise their Leader's power to 6000. In this case, does this Character's power become 6000?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not.This Character's [When Attacking] effect makes its base power the same as your opponent's Leader at the time of activation(Please see the official website for this card's updated text.)"
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-013",
        "title": "OP06-013 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Do I play this card onto my field when I activate its [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you do not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-014",
        "title": "OP06-014 Ratchet",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect to trash 2 cards from my hand, and give 2 of my Characters +1000 power each?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-018",
        "title": "OP06-018 Gum-Gum King Kong Gatling",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose to give +3000 power and +1000 power to different Characters according to this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-023",
        "title": "OP06-023 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: Does my opponent's rested Leader chosen according to this [On Play] effect become active during my opponent's next Refresh Phase?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it becomes active, but that Leader cannot attack during that turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-024",
        "title": "OP06-024 Ikaros Much",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to play \"OP06-034 Hyouzou\" from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot.(Please see the official website for the updated text of \"OP06-034 Hyouzou\".)"
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-024",
        "title": "OP06-024 Ikaros Much",
        "question": "Q: If I play this Character when my Leader has the {New Fish-Man Pirates} type, do I still need to add 1 of my Life cards to my hand if I don't play a Character from my hand according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you still need to add 1 Life card to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-026",
        "title": "OP06-026 Koushirou",
        "question": "Q: Can my Leader or Characters other than the Character set as active by this effect attack my opponent's Leader during the turn in which I activate this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, they cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-026",
        "title": "OP06-026 Koushirou",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's [On Play] effect if I have already attacked my opponent's Leader during this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-028",
        "title": "OP06-028 Zeo",
        "question": "Q: I attacked with this Character with a DON!! card given to it. If I do not set 1 of my DON!! cards as active, do I still need to add 1 of my Life cards to my hand according to this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you still need to add 1 Life card to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-035",
        "title": "OP06-035 Hody Jones",
        "question": "Q: If I play this Character but do not rest any Characters or DON!! cards, do I still need to add 1 of my Life cards to my hand according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you still need to add 1 Life card to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-038",
        "title": "OP06-038 The Billion-fold World Trichiliocosm",
        "question": "Q: I had 7 rested cards on my field when I rested 1 DON!! card and activated this card's [Counter] effect. Can I give my Leader or a Character card a total +4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-038",
        "title": "OP06-038 The Billion-fold World Trichiliocosm",
        "question": "Q: I activated this Event when I had 3 rested DON!! cards on my field, 1 rested Leader, and 1 rested Character, and my Leader had 3 DON!! cards given to it. Can I give my Leader or a Character card a total +4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-042",
        "title": "OP06-042 Vinsmoke Reiju",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Your Turn] effect when one of my DON!! cards is returned to my DON!! deck by my opponent's card effect during my turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-043",
        "title": "OP06-043 Aramaki",
        "question": "Q: Can I still activate this [Activate: Main] effect if there is neither my nor my opponent's field has a Character with a cost of 2 or less?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-044",
        "title": "OP06-044 Gion",
        "question": "Q: Having played this Charater, I targeted my opponent's Leader for an attack. At this time, my opponent had only 1 card in their hand, and they activated \"ST03-017 Love-Love Mellow\" from their hand. What happens to this Character's effect?",
        "answer": "A: A card is drawn according to the effect of \"ST03-017 Love-Love Mellow\" and, after all processing is completed, this Character's [Your Turn] effect is activated."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-048",
        "title": "OP06-048 Zeff",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent activates an Event card's [Trigger] effect during my turn, can I activate this Character's [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-048",
        "title": "OP06-048 Zeff",
        "question": "Q: My opponent activated the [Blocker] of their \"ST03-003 Crocodile\" during my turn when this Character's cost was 2 or less. At this time, if I place this Character at the bottom of my deck according to the effect of \"ST03-003 Crocodile\" (\"[DON!! x1] [On Block] Place up to 1 Character with a cost of 2 or less at the bottom of the owner's deck.\"), what happens to this Character's [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: After your opponent activates the [Blocker] of \"ST03-003 Crocodile\" and changes the attack target, you can choose to trash 4 cards from the top of your deck according to this Character's [Your Turn] effect, and then you will place this Character at the bottom of your deck according to the [On Block] effect of \"ST03-003 Crocodile\"."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-051",
        "title": "OP06-051 Tsuru",
        "question": "Q: Does my opponent choose which Character to return to their hand according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. Your opponent chooses 1 Character on their field and returns it to their hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-054",
        "title": "OP06-054 Borsalino",
        "question": "Q: After activating this Character's [Blocker], the number of cards in my hand became 6 or more during that battle. What happens to the attack target?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, attack processing proceeds with this Character as the attack target."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-056",
        "title": "OP06-056 Ama no Murakumo Sword",
        "question": "Q: When my opponent is to place 2 Characters at the bottom of their deck according to this [Main] effect, which player decides the order in which they are placed?",
        "answer": "A: The owner of the cards to be placed at the bottom of the deck according to this effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-056",
        "title": "OP06-056 Ama no Murakumo Sword",
        "question": "Q: When my opponent is to place 2 Characters at the bottom of their deck according to this [Main] effect, am I allowed to know the order in which they are placed?",
        "answer": "A: No, you are not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-058",
        "title": "OP06-058 Gravity Blade Raging Tiger",
        "question": "Q: When my opponent is to place 2 Characters at the bottom of their deck according to this [Main] effect, which player decides the order in which they are placed?",
        "answer": "A: The owner of the cards to be placed at the bottom of the deck according to this effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-058",
        "title": "OP06-058 Gravity Blade Raging Tiger",
        "question": "Q: When my opponent is to place 2 Characters at the bottom of their deck according to this [Main] effect, am I allowed to know the order in which they are placed?",
        "answer": "A: No, you are not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-061",
        "title": "OP06-061 Vinsmoke Ichiji",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [On Play] effect, gave 1 of my opponent's Characters −2000 power, and this Character gained [Rush]. Then, during that turn, the number of DON!! cards on my field became greater than the number on my opponent's field. What happens to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Your opponent's Character will continue to be given −2000 power during that turn, and this Character will continue to have [Rush]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-065",
        "title": "OP06-065 Vinsmoke Niji",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to return my opponent's Character with a cost of 2 or less to their hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-072",
        "title": "OP06-072 Cosette",
        "question": "Q: My Leader has the {GERMA 66} type and the number of DON!! cards on my field was 2 less than the number on my opponent's field when my opponent's Character attacked. My opponent's [When Attacking] effect reduced the number of my opponent's DON!! cards, meaning I no longer have at least 2 fewer DON!! cards on my field than my opponent. Can I activate this Character's [Blocker] in response to this attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-074",
        "title": "OP06-074 Zephyr (Navy)",
        "question": "Q: If the Character I choose according to this [On Play] effect is subject to effects such as \"gains +1000 power during this turn.\", does this [On Play] effect reset the Character's power to its base power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-074",
        "title": "OP06-074 Zephyr (Navy)",
        "question": "Q: If I use this Character's [On Play] effect to negate the effect of and K.O. my opponent's Character with an [On K.O.] effect, will the [On K.O.] effect of my opponent's Character be activated?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-074",
        "title": "OP06-074 Zephyr (Navy)",
        "question": "Q: I used the [On Play] effect of \"OP01-006 Otama\" to give −2000 power to my opponent's Character with a base power of 7000. Can I use this Character's [On Play] effect to K.O. my opponent's Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-074",
        "title": "OP06-074 Zephyr (Navy)",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this Character's [On Play] effect to K.O. a Character with 5000 power or less that is subject to the [On Play] effect of my opponent's \"OP04-083 Sabo\" (\"[On Play] None of your Characters can be K.O.'d by effects until the start of your next turn.\")?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-074",
        "title": "OP06-074 Zephyr (Navy)",
        "question": "Q: My opponent played \"OP02-004 Edward.Newgate\" in their previous turn and used its [On Play] effect to give their Leader +2000 power. I then used this [On Play] effect to negate its effect. Does my opponent's Leader still have +2000 power according to [Edward.Newgate]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will still have +2000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-074",
        "title": "OP06-074 Zephyr (Navy)",
        "question": "Q: Can a Character that has had its effect negated according to this [On Play] effect be subsequently chosen as the target of an effect by another card during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-074",
        "title": "OP06-074 Zephyr (Navy)",
        "question": "Q: Is a Character that has had its effect negated according to this [On Play] effect treated as a \"Character with no base effect\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, it is not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-080",
        "title": "OP06-080 Gecko Moria",
        "question": "Q: If I trash \"OP06-094 Lola\" from my hand according to this [When Attacking] effect, can I then play that trashed card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-083",
        "title": "OP06-083 Oars",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is subject to a \"gains +1000 power during this turn\" effect due to another card or DON!! card, does this [Activate: Main] effect reset this Character's power to its base power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-083",
        "title": "OP06-083 Oars",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Activate: Main] effect after this Character gained [Banish] according to the [On Play] effect of \"OP06-101 O-Nami\". What happens if I then attack with this Character and deal damage to my opponent's Leader?",
        "answer": "A: No Trigger is activated according to this damage and your opponent trashes a Life card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-083",
        "title": "OP06-083 Oars",
        "question": "Q: Can a Character that has had its effect negated according to this [On Play] effect be subsequently chosen as the target of an effect by another card during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-083",
        "title": "OP06-083 Oars",
        "question": "Q: Is a Character that has had its effect negated according to this [On Play] effect treated as a \"Character with no base effect\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, it is not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-086",
        "title": "OP06-086 Gecko Moria",
        "question": "Q: If I only play 1 Character card according to this [On Play] effect, do I play that Character rested?",
        "answer": "A: No, it is played as active."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-092",
        "title": "OP06-092 Brook",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent's Character with a cost of 4 or less and an [On K.O.] effect is trashed according to this [On Play] effect, is that [On K.O.] effect activated?",
        "answer": "A: No, it is not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-092",
        "title": "OP06-092 Brook",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to trash my opponent's \"OP02-114 Borsalino\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-092",
        "title": "OP06-092 Brook",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose \"• Your opponent places 3 cards from their trash at the bottom of their deck in any order.\" according to this [On Play] effect if my opponent has 2 or less cards in their trash?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, your opponent will place all the cards in their trash at the bottom of their deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-102",
        "title": "OP06-102 Kamakiri",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this effect to place my opponent's Stage with a cost of 1 at the bottom of their deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-103",
        "title": "OP06-103 Kawamatsu",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to place a Character that has had its power reduced to below 0 by other effects at the top or bottom of my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-106",
        "title": "OP06-106 Kouzuki Hiyori",
        "question": "Q: Do I need to reveal the card added from my hand to my Life cards to my opponent according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. Place the card on the top of your Life cards face-down without showing it to your opponent."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-107",
        "title": "OP06-107 Kouzuki Momonosuke",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [On Play] effect to add \"OP01-041 Kouzuki Momonosuke\" to my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-111",
        "title": "OP06-111 Braham",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this effect to place my opponent's Stage with a cost of 1 at the bottom of their deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-114",
        "title": "OP06-114 Wyper",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this effect to place my opponent's Stage with a cost of 1 at the bottom of their deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-115",
        "title": "OP06-115 You're the One Who Should Disappear.",
        "question": "Q: I had 0 Life cards and 0 cards in my hand when I activated this [Trigger] effect. Can I add up to 1 card from the top of my deck to the top of my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-118",
        "title": "OP06-118 Roronoa Zoro",
        "question": "Q: I attacked with this Character and did not activate its [When Attacking] effect. If I then use its [Activate: Main] effect to set it as active and attack again, can I activate this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-083",
        "title": "OP06-083 Oars",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [Activate: Main] effect on the turn this Character is played, can this Character attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot attack. This Character cannot attack on the turn it is played unless it gains [Rush] according to another card's effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-086",
        "title": "OP06-086 Gecko Moria",
        "question": "Q: I used this [On Play] effect to play Character A as active and Character B rested. Can I choose the order in which I activate the [On Play] effects of Character A and Character B?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the player who played these Characters can activate their effects in the order of their choosing."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-086",
        "title": "OP06-086 Gecko Moria",
        "question": "Q: I had 4 Characters including this Character when I played this Character. I used this [On Play] effect to play Character A as active, and then trashed Character A while playing Character B rested. Can I activate Character A's [On Play] effect at this time?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-091",
        "title": "OP06-091 Victoria Cindry",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to trash 5 cards from the top of my opponent's deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-042",
        "title": "OP06-042 Vinsmoke Reiju",
        "question": "Q: I had 5 cards in my hand when I activated the [Activate: Main] effect of \"OP06-068 Vinsmoke Reiju\" on my field, and returned 1 DON!! card from my field to my DON!! deck and played \"OP06-069 Vinsmoke Reiju\" from my trash. In this case, after drawing 2 cards according to the [On Play] effect of \"OP06-069 Vinsmoke Reiju\", can I draw 1 card according to this Leader's [Your Turn] effect to bring the number of cards in my hand to 8?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP06-116",
        "title": "OP06-116 Reject",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Main] effect when my opponent did not have 1 Life card, and chose \"If your opponent has 1 Life card, deal 1 damage to your opponent. Then, add 1 card from the top of your Life cards to your hand.\". In this case, can I add 1 card from the top of my Life cards to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-001",
        "title": "OP05-001 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: If a Character with a base power of 4000 or less is attacked and its power becomes 5000 or more in the Counter Step when it would be K.O.'d, can I use this [Opponent's Turn] effect to give the Character −1000 power instead of it being K.O.'d?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-001",
        "title": "OP05-001 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: When my Character with 5000 power or more would have been K.O.'d on my opponent's turn, I decided not to use this [Opponent's Turn] effect to give this Character −1000 power instead. Then, during that turn, if another one of my Characters with 5000 power or more would be K.O.'d, can I use this [Opponent's Turn] effect to give it −1000 power instead?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can.Because “you may give that Character −1000 power during this turn instead” has not been resolved, the [Once Per Turn] restriction does not apply."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-002",
        "title": "OP05-002 Belo Betty",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give this Leader +3000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-003",
        "title": "OP05-003 Inazuma",
        "question": "Q: I played this Character when I had a Character other than this Character with 7000 power or more. If I now no longer have a Character with 7000 power or more, can this Character still attack during this turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-003",
        "title": "OP05-003 Inazuma",
        "question": "Q: If this Character attacks on the turn in which it is played and, during that battle, I no longer have a Character with 7000 power or more other than this Character, what happens to the attack?",
        "answer": "A: The processing of that battle proceeds as is."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-003",
        "title": "OP05-003 Inazuma",
        "question": "Q: If I had no Characters with 7000 power or more other than this Character when I played it, but during the turn I gain a Character with 7000 power or more, can this Character attack on this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-005",
        "title": "OP05-005 Karasu",
        "question": "Q: Can I still activate this [When Attacking] effect if my Leader does not have the {Revolutionary Army} type?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-007",
        "title": "OP05-007 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to K.O. 1 Character with 4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-007",
        "title": "OP05-007 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to K.O. a Character with −2000 power and a Character with 6000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-008",
        "title": "OP05-008 Chaka",
        "question": "Q: Can I give my Leader and 1 of my Characters 1 DON!! card each?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-019",
        "title": "OP05-019 Fire Fist",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose to give −4000 power to a Character and K.O. a different Character with 0 power or less according to this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-022",
        "title": "OP05-022 Donquixote Rosinante",
        "question": "Q: I activated this Leader's [Blocker] and made it the target of the attack. What happens if my Leader loses the battle?",
        "answer": "A: You will take damage."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-030",
        "title": "OP05-030 Donquixote Rosinante",
        "question": "Q: If this Character and my opponent's \"ST02-010 Basil Hawkins\" battle and I use this [Opponent's Turn] effect to trash this card instead, can my opponent activate the [Your Turn] effect of \"ST02-010 Basil Hawkins\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-030",
        "title": "OP05-030 Donquixote Rosinante",
        "question": "Q: If this Character and 2 of my rested Characters would be K.O.'d by the [On Play] effect of \"OP01-094 Kaido\", can I use this Character's [Opponent's Turn] effect to prevent both of my 2 rested Characters from being K.O.'d?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-030",
        "title": "OP05-030 Donquixote Rosinante",
        "question": "Q: I used this [Opponent's Turn] effect to trash this rested Character when it would have been K.O.'d. Can I activate the \"When your opponent's Character is K.O.'d, set this Leader as active.\" effect of \"OP03-076 Rob Lucci\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-031",
        "title": "OP05-031 Buffalo",
        "question": "Q: If I have 2 rested Characters including this attacking Character, can I use this [When Attacking] effect to set 1 of my rested Characters with a cost of 1 as active?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-032",
        "title": "OP05-032 Pica",
        "question": "Q: Can I rest my Character with a cost of 3 or more that would be K.O.'d at the same time as this Character to prevent this Character from being K.O.'d?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-039",
        "title": "OP05-039 Stick-Stickem Meteora",
        "question": "Q: If I K.O. an attacking Character with this [Counter] effect, what happens to the battle?",
        "answer": "A: If there is no attacking Character or Character being attacked on the field at the end of that Counter Step, the battle will end without moving to the Damage Step."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-040",
        "title": "OP05-040 Birdcage",
        "question": "Q: Can I still use this [End of Your Turn] effect to K.O. all rested Characters with a cost of 5 or less if my Leader is not [Donquixote Doflamingo]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-040",
        "title": "OP05-040 Birdcage",
        "question": "Q: Is this [End of Your Turn] effect always activated at the end of my turn when I have 10 DON!! cards on my field?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it is always activated."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-047",
        "title": "OP05-047 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: If I have 4 or more cards in my hand, will this Character still gain +1000 power according to this [On Block] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-047",
        "title": "OP05-047 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: If, after activating this Character's [Blocker], the number of cards in my hand goes from 4 or more to 3 or less in the Counter Step, can I draw 1 card and give this Character +1000 power according to this [On Block] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-058",
        "title": "OP05-058 It's a Waste of Human Life!!",
        "question": "Q: In what order should players trash cards from their hands?",
        "answer": "A: First, the player whose turn it is and who activated this [Main] effect chooses cards in their own hand and trashes them. Then, their opponent chooses cards in their own hand and trashes them."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-058",
        "title": "OP05-058 It's a Waste of Human Life!!",
        "question": "Q: Which player decides the order in which Characters are placed at the bottom of their deck?",
        "answer": "A: First, the player whose turn it is puts their Characters with a cost of 3 or less at the bottom of their deck in any order they choose. Then, their opponent puts their Characters with a cost of 3 or less at the bottom of their deck in any order they choose."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-062",
        "title": "OP05-062 O-Nami",
        "question": "Q: I played this Character when I had 10 DON!! cards on my field. If I now have 9 or less DON!! cards on my field, can I still activate this Character's [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-062",
        "title": "OP05-062 O-Nami",
        "question": "Q: Is this card treated as a card with the card name \"Nami\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, it is not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-075",
        "title": "OP05-075 Mr.1(Daz.Bonez)",
        "question": "Q: My opponent attacked and I used this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect to play another \"OP05-075 Mr.1(Daz.Bonez)\". Can I activate the [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect of the \"OP05-075 Mr.1(Daz.Bonez)\" I just played during this attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-079",
        "title": "OP05-079 Viola",
        "question": "Q: Which player chooses which cards are returned to the deck according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: The player who did not activate this [On Play] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-082",
        "title": "OP05-082 Shirahoshi",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has 5 or less cards in their hand, can I still place 2 cards from my trash at the bottom of my deck according to this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can, but your opponent will not trash 1 card from their hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-084",
        "title": "OP05-084 Saint Charlos",
        "question": "Q: If the only Characters on my field are {Celestial Dragons} type Characters, and I play a non-{Celestial Dragons} type Character, can I activate that Character's [On Play] effect with all my opponent's Characters still having −4 cost?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-086",
        "title": "OP05-086 Nefeltari Vivi",
        "question": "Q: I played this Character when I had 10 cards in my trash. If the number of cards in my trash then becomes 9 or less, can I still activate this Character's [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-087",
        "title": "OP05-087 Hakuba",
        "question": "Q: What happens if I choose my \"OP03-088 Fukurou\" as the Character to K.O. according to this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Your \"OP03-088 Fukurou\" will not be K.O.'d, and you will not be able to give 1 of your opponent's Characters −5 cost according to this [When Attacking] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-087",
        "title": "OP05-087 Hakuba",
        "question": "Q: What happens if I choose my \"OP04-082 Kyros\" as the Character to K.O. according to this [When Attacking] effect, and then rest my Leader or [Corrida Coliseum] instead of K.O.'ing it?",
        "answer": "A: Your \"OP04-082 Kyros\" will not be K.O.'d, and you will not be able to give 1 of your opponent's Characters −5 cost according to this [When Attacking] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-091",
        "title": "OP05-091 Rebecca",
        "question": "Q: Can I add a black card with a cost of 3 to my hand and then play that card rested according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-092",
        "title": "OP05-092 Saint Rosward",
        "question": "Q: If the only Characters on my field are {Celestial Dragons} type Characters, and I play a non-{Celestial Dragons} type Character, can I activate that Character's [On Play] effect with all my opponent's Characters still having −6 cost?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-095",
        "title": "OP05-095 Dragon Claw",
        "question": "Q: If I have 14 cards in my trash, can I still use this [Counter] effect to K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 4 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-098",
        "title": "OP05-098 Enel",
        "question": "Q: If I take damage when I have 1 Life card remaining and that Life card has a Trigger, which will activate first: this [Opponent's Turn] effect or the [Trigger]?",
        "answer": "A: You will choose whether to activate the [Trigger] effect. If you choose to activate it, this [Opponent's Turn] effect will activate after that effect has been processed."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-098",
        "title": "OP05-098 Enel",
        "question": "Q: I took damage when I had 1 Life card remaining. That Life card was \"OP03-118 Ikoku Sovereignty\", so I activated the [Trigger] effect and my number of Life cards went from 0 to 1. In this case, can I still activate this [Opponent's Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-098",
        "title": "OP05-098 Enel",
        "question": "Q: I took damage when I had 1 Life card remaining. That Life card was \"OP05-106 Shura\", so I activated the [Trigger] effect. What will activate first, this Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect or the [On Play] effect of \"OP05-106 Shura\"?",
        "answer": "A: The player who activated this Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect and the [On Play] effect of \"OP05-106 Shura\" can activate the effects in the order they wish."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-098",
        "title": "OP05-098 Enel",
        "question": "Q: I took 2 damage from my opponent's card with [Double Attack] when I had 1 Life card remaining. In this case, do I take the second damage after I have taken the first damage and activated this [Opponent's Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. After you have taken 2 damage and the Damage Step has ended, you can then use this [Opponent's Turn] effect to add 1 card from the top of your deck to the top of your Life cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-100",
        "title": "OP05-100 Enel",
        "question": "Q: If this Character would leave my field due to one of my effects, can I use this [Once Per Turn] effect to trash 1 Life card instead?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-100",
        "title": "OP05-100 Enel",
        "question": "Q: If I choose this Character with the \"You may return 1 Character to your hand:\" effect of \"OP01-047 Trafalgar Law\" and trash 1 of my Life cards instead, can I still use the effect of \"OP01-047 Trafalgar Law\" to play a Character with a cost of 3 or less from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-100",
        "title": "OP05-100 Enel",
        "question": "Q: Is this Character's [Rush] also negated if there is a [Monkey D.Luffy] Character present?",
        "answer": "A: No, it is not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-101",
        "title": "OP05-101 Ohm",
        "question": "Q: If I do not reveal a [Holly] when I look at 5 cards from the top of my deck, can I still play a [Holly] from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-107",
        "title": "OP05-107 Lieutenant Spacey",
        "question": "Q: If I activate the [Trigger] effect of \"ST09-002 Uzuki Tempura\" (\"[Trigger] Rest up to 1 of your opponent's Characters with a cost of 2 or less and add this card to your hand.\") and add it to my hand, can I activate this Character's [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-109",
        "title": "OP05-109 Pagaya",
        "question": "Q: Is this Character's effect also activated when my opponent activates a [Trigger]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it is."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP05-001",
        "title": "OP05-001 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: If the [On Play] effect of my opponent's \"OP01-094 Kaido\" would K.O. 2 of my Characters with 5000 power or more, can I use this [Opponent's Turn] effect of my Leader with 1 DON!! card given to it to prevent those 2 Characters from being K.O.'d?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, you can choose whether both of your 2 Characters with 5000 power or more will be K.O.'d, or neither will be K.O.'d but be given −1000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-002",
        "title": "OP04-002 Igaram",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Activate: Main] effect when my active Leader's power has been reduced to 0 by another effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, your Leader will have −5000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-003",
        "title": "OP04-003 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: What is \"base power\"?",
        "answer": "A: The power value written on the card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-004",
        "title": "OP04-004 Karoo",
        "question": "Q: What happens according to this [Activate: Main] effect if I don't have enough rested DON!! cards in my cost area to give 1 to each of my {Alabasta} type Characters?",
        "answer": "A: You will select as many {Alabasta} type Characters as you have rested DON!! cards in your cost area and give each of them 1 rested DON!! card from your cost area."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-004",
        "title": "OP04-004 Karoo",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give a Character a DON!! card that has already been given to another Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This [Activate: Main] effect directs you to give a rested DON!! card from your cost area."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-006",
        "title": "OP04-006 Koza",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [When Attacking] effect when my active Leader's power has been reduced to 0 by another effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, your Leader will have −5000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-008",
        "title": "OP04-008 Chaka",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to give −3000 power to a Character and K.O. a different Character with 0 power or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-009",
        "title": "OP04-009 Super Spot-Billed Duck Troops",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [When Attacking] effect when my active Leader's power has been reduced to 0 by another effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, your Leader will have −5000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-011",
        "title": "OP04-011 Nami",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose not to reveal a card from the top of my deck on using this Character to attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, you must reveal a card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-016",
        "title": "OP04-016 Bad Manners Kick Course",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose not to trash 1 card from my hand on activating this card during the Counter Step?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, you cannot give 1 of your cards +3000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-017",
        "title": "OP04-017 Happiness Punch",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader is active, can I use this [Counter] effect to give 1 card a total of −3000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-018",
        "title": "OP04-018 Enchanting Vertigo Dance",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to give 1 of my opponent's Characters a total of −4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-019",
        "title": "OP04-019 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [End of Your Turn] effect to set DON!! cards already given to a Character as active?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-020",
        "title": "OP04-020 Issho",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [End of Your Turn] effect to rest DON!! cards that were changed from rested to active by another of my [End of Your Turn] effects?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-024",
        "title": "OP04-024 Sugar",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is rested on a turn in which I have not yet used this [Opponent's Turn] effect, can I use this [Opponent's Turn] effect to rest my opponent's Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-024",
        "title": "OP04-024 Sugar",
        "question": "Q: If I have not yet used this [Opponent's Turn] effect during a turn, can I decide not to use this [Opponent's Turn] effect to rest a Character my opponent plays, and instead rest the next Character played?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-024",
        "title": "OP04-024 Sugar",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have the {Donquixote Pirates} type, can I still use this [On Play] effect to rest up to 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 4 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-024",
        "title": "OP04-024 Sugar",
        "question": "Q: I had this Character on my field when my opponent played [OP03-013 Marco] and used its [On Play] effect to K.O. this Character. In this case, can I still activate this Character's [Opponent's Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-026",
        "title": "OP04-026 Senor Pink",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this Character's [When Attacking] effect and this Character then leaves the field, can I still set up to 1 of my DON!! cards as active at the end of this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-028",
        "title": "OP04-028 Diamante",
        "question": "Q: When calculating my active DON!! cards for this [End of Your Turn] effect, can I include DON!! cards that have been changed from rested to active by another of my [End of Your Turn] effects?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-031",
        "title": "OP04-031 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: If I select my opponent's rested Character for this [On Play] effect and it then becomes active during that turn due to another effect, will that Character be rested during my opponent's next Refresh Phase?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-031",
        "title": "OP04-031 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: Which player chooses the Leader or Character cards that do not become active according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: The player who activated this [On Play] effect chooses the cards upon activating this [On Play] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-031",
        "title": "OP04-031 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose 3 of my opponent's Characters according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-033",
        "title": "OP04-033 Machvise",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have the {Donquixote Pirates} type, can I still use this [On Play] effect to set up to 1 of my DON!! cards as active?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-033",
        "title": "OP04-033 Machvise",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this Character's [On Play] effect and this Character then leaves the field, can I still set up to 1 of my DON!! cards as active at the end of this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-034",
        "title": "OP04-034 Lao.G",
        "question": "Q: When calculating my active DON!! cards for this [End of Your Turn] effect, can I include DON!! cards that have been changed from rested to active by another of my [End of Your Turn] effects?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-035",
        "title": "OP04-035 Spiderweb",
        "question": "Q: If a Character that is being attacked is set to active by this [Counter] effect, is the attack nullified?",
        "answer": "A: No. The attack is not nullified because the attack's target has already been set."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-035",
        "title": "OP04-035 Spiderweb",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate the [Blocker] of a Character set as active by this [Counter] effect during this battle?",
        "answer": "A: No. You cannot activate it because this battle's Block Step has already concluded."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-036",
        "title": "OP04-036 Donquixote Family",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this card from my hand during the Main Phase of my turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-038",
        "title": "OP04-038 The Weak Do Not Have the Right to Choose How They Die!!!",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Main]/[Counter] effect to rest a Character with a cost of 6 or less and then K.O. that Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-040",
        "title": "OP04-040 Queen",
        "question": "Q: If I have a total of 4 or less cards in my Life area and hand, and I have a Character with a cost of 8 or more, can I use this [When Attacking] effect to draw 1 card without adding up to 1 card from the top of my deck to my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-043",
        "title": "OP04-043 Ulti",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to return my own Character to my hand or the bottom of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-043",
        "title": "OP04-043 Ulti",
        "question": "Q: Which player chooses whether to return the selected Character to their hand or the bottom of their deck according to this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: The choice is made by the player who activated this [When Attacking] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-046",
        "title": "OP04-046 Queen",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to add 2 [Plague Rounds] or 2 [Ice Oni] cards to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-047",
        "title": "OP04-047 Ice Oni",
        "question": "Q: I attacked with this Character and won the battle against my opponent's Character. In this case, is the Character that was K.O.'d in this battle placed at the bottom of the owner's deck at the end of the battle?",
        "answer": "A: No, the Character is trashed."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-053",
        "title": "OP04-053 Page One",
        "question": "Q: If I activate my Event's [Trigger] effect, can I use this [DON!! x1] effect to draw a card?",
        "answer": "A: No. Activating a [Trigger] is not the same as activating an Event."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-055",
        "title": "OP04-055 Plague Rounds",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [Main] effect, trash 1 [Ice Oni] from my hand, and place 1 Character with a cost of 4 or less at the bottom of the owner's deck, can I choose not to play an [Ice Oni]?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-055",
        "title": "OP04-055 Plague Rounds",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to place my own Character with a cost of 4 or less at the bottom of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-055",
        "title": "OP04-055 Plague Rounds",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Main] effect and trash 1 [Ice Oni] from my hand or play 1 [Ice Oni] from my trash without placing 1 Character with a cost of 4 or less at the bottom of the owner's deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-058",
        "title": "OP04-058 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: If this card's [Opponent's Turn] effect is activated by a [Trigger] effect such as \"[Trigger] DON!! −1: Play this card.\", which effect is activated first, the [On Play] effect of the Character played according to this [Trigger] or this [Opponent's Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, the player with this Leader can choose the order in which the [On Play] effect of the Character played according to the [Trigger] effect and this [Opponent's Turn] effect are activated."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-064",
        "title": "OP04-064 Ms. All Sunday",
        "question": "Q: My Leader is [OP04-058 Crocodile] and I have 6 DON!! cards on my field when I activate this Character's [Trigger], return 2 DON!! cards from my field to my DON!! deck, and play this Character with 4 DON!! cards on my field. At this time, can I use this Character's [On Play] effect to draw 1 card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Your Leader's [Opponent's Turn] effect will have activated first, so you will have added 1 DON!! card, meaning you have 5 DON!! cards. Then, you will add 1 more DON!! card with this Character's [On Play] effect, so you will be able to draw 1 card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-064",
        "title": "OP04-064 Ms. All Sunday",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Trigger] effect to return DON!! cards to my DON!! deck without playing this Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. In this case, you must play this Character."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-066",
        "title": "OP04-066 Miss.Valentine(Mikita)",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to add another [Miss.Valentine(Mikita)] card to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-066",
        "title": "OP04-066 Miss.Valentine(Mikita)",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Trigger] effect to return DON!! cards to my DON!! deck without playing this Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. In this case, you must play this Character."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-069",
        "title": "OP04-069 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Trigger] effect to return DON!! cards to my DON!! deck without playing this Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. In this case, you must play this Character."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-079",
        "title": "OP04-079 Orlumbus",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose a Character with a \"cannot be K.O.'d by effects.\" effect for this [Activate: Main] effect's \"K.O. 1 of your {Dressrosa} type Characters.\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, after you give up to 1 of your opponent's Characters −4 cost during this turn and trash 2 cards from the top of your deck, the Character you chose will not be K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-079",
        "title": "OP04-079 Orlumbus",
        "question": "Q: If this is the only Character I have, can I choose not to K.O. my Character according to this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-079",
        "title": "OP04-079 Orlumbus",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Activate: Main] effect and choose not to trash cards from my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-081",
        "title": "OP04-081 Cavendish",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [When Attacking] effect and choose not to trash cards from my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-082",
        "title": "OP04-082 Kyros",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [On Play] effect and choose not to trash a card from my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-083",
        "title": "OP04-083 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: Will Characters I play after activating this [On Play] effect be unable to be K.O.'d by effects until the start of my next turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, they will be able to be K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-085",
        "title": "OP04-085 Suleiman",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [On Play]/[When Attacking] effect and choose not to trash a card from my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-091",
        "title": "OP04-091 Leo",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [On Play] effect and choose not to trash cards from my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-093",
        "title": "OP04-093 Gum-Gum King Kong Gun",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Main] effect when I had 14 cards in my trash. At this time, will my chosen Character gain [Double Attack]?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, you will have 15 cards in your trash including this card, so the Character will gain [Double Attack]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-094",
        "title": "OP04-094 Trueno Bastardo",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Main] effect when I had 14 cards in my trash. At this time, can I choose a Character with a cost of 6?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, you will have 15 cards in your trash including this card, so you will be able to choose a Character with a cost of 6 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-095",
        "title": "OP04-095 Barrier!!",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Counter] effect when I had 14 cards in my trash. At this time, can I give 1 of my Leader or Character cards a total of +4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-095",
        "title": "OP04-095 Barrier!!",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Counter] effect when I had 15 or more cards in my trash. At this time, can I choose 2 of my Leader or Character cards and give them +2000 power each?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-099",
        "title": "OP04-099 Olin",
        "question": "Q: My Leader took 1 damage while I had 2 Life cards. At this time, I checked the card at the top of my Life cards and it was this card. Can I play this card according to this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-111",
        "title": "OP04-111 Hera",
        "question": "Q: If I have 2 of this card on my field, can I use 1 of their [Activate: Main] effects to trash the other card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-118",
        "title": "OP04-118 Nefeltari Vivi",
        "question": "Q: If a Character that does not have [Rush] gains [Rush] according to this Character's effect, can that Character attack on the turn in which it is played if it has had its cost reduced to less than 3 by another effect during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-119",
        "title": "OP04-119 Donquixote Rosinante",
        "question": "Q: What is \"base cost\"?",
        "answer": "A: The cost value written on the card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-090",
        "title": "OP04-090 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: When returning 7 cards from my trash to the bottom of my deck according to this [Activate: Main] effect, do I reveal both the cards and their order to my opponent?",
        "answer": "A: After revealing the 7 cards to be returned from your trash to your deck to your opponent, rearrange their order out of your opponent's view and place them at the bottom of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP04-119",
        "title": "OP04-119 Donquixote Rosinante",
        "question": "Q: When this rested Character and my active Characters with a base cost of 5 would be K.O.'d be a single effect at the same time during my opponent's turn, does this [Opponent's Turn] effect still prevent my active Characters with a base cost of 5 from being K.O.'d?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does. Your \"OP04-119 Donquixote Rosinante\" will be K.O.'d, but your active Characters with a base cost of 5 will not be K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-001",
        "title": "OP03-001 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: Does my Leader's \"When this Leader attacks\" effect activate before my opponent's [Blocker] or Counter activate?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it activates before your opponent's [Blocker] or Counter activate."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-001",
        "title": "OP03-001 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: Does my Leader's \"When this Leader...is attacked\" effect activate before my Counter activates?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it activates before your Counter activates."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-001",
        "title": "OP03-001 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: Does my Leader's \"When this Leader...is attacked\" effect activate before my opponent's [When Attacking] effects or \"When...attacks\" effects activate?",
        "answer": "A: No. Your opponent's [When Attacking] effects or \"When...attacks\" effects activate first."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-001",
        "title": "OP03-001 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: Does my Leader's \"When this Leader...is attacked\" effect activate before my [Blocker] activates?",
        "answer": "A: No, it activates after your [Blocker] activates. However, if you activate your Character's [Blocker], that Character will become the target of the attack, so you will be unable to activate this Leader's \"When this Leader...is attacked\" effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-001",
        "title": "OP03-001 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: After I activate a Counter during my Counter Step, can I activate my Leader's \"When this Leader...is attacked\" effect to increase its power?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-001",
        "title": "OP03-001 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: If my Character is attacked, can I activate this Leader's \"When this Leader...is attacked\" effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-005",
        "title": "OP03-005 Thatch",
        "question": "Q: If this card is moved once to my hand or deck on the turn in which this [Activate: Main] effect is activated, should I trash this card at the end of the turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, do not trash this card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-012",
        "title": "OP03-012 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate the [On K.O.] effect of my Character trashed by this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-012",
        "title": "OP03-012 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to trash a Character with a base power of 3000 or less that had its power increased to 4000 or more, for example by the giving of DON!! cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-016",
        "title": "OP03-016 Flame Emperor",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [Main] effect and choose not to K.O. a Character, can my Leader [Portgas.D.Ace] gain [Double Attack] and +3000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-027",
        "title": "OP03-027 Sham",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have the {East Blue} type and I do not have [Buchi] on my field, can I use this [On Play] effect to play 1 [Buchi] from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-028",
        "title": "OP03-028 Jango",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to set as active 1 of my Characters with a cost of 6 or less that does not have the {East Blue} type?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-028",
        "title": "OP03-028 Jango",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [On Play] effect and choose \"• Rest this Character and up to 1 of your opponent's Characters.\", can I decide not to rest this Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-033",
        "title": "OP03-033 Hatchan",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have the {East Blue} type, can I activate this [Trigger]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. If you activate this [Trigger], you must trash this card without playing it."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-036",
        "title": "OP03-036 Out-of-the-Bag",
        "question": "Q: Does \"your [Kuro]\" refer to my Leader [Kuro] or my Character [Kuro] cards?",
        "answer": "A: It refers to both your Leader [Kuro] and your Character [Kuro] cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-040",
        "title": "OP03-040 Nami",
        "question": "Q: Does this \"When this Leader's attack deals damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activate before a [Trigger] resulting from that damage?",
        "answer": "A: First, your opponent checks their Life in accordance with the damage dealt, and then this \"When this Leader's attack deals damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activates. After that, if the checked Life card has a [Trigger], your opponent can choose to activate it."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-041",
        "title": "OP03-041 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: Does this \"When this Character's attack deals damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activate before a [Trigger] resulting from that damage?",
        "answer": "A: First, your opponent checks their Life in accordance with the damage dealt, and then this \"When this Character's attack deals damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activates. After that, if the checked Life card has a [Trigger], your opponent can choose to activate it."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-043",
        "title": "OP03-043 Gaimon",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this \"When you deal damage to your opponent's Life\" effect when the attack of a Character or Leader other than this card deals damage to my opponent's Life?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-043",
        "title": "OP03-043 Gaimon",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this \"When you deal damage to your opponent's Life\" effect when my opponent's Life card is moved to their hand or trashed due to the effect of another card?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-043",
        "title": "OP03-043 Gaimon",
        "question": "Q: If a Character with [Double Attack] deals 2 damage to my opponent's Life, can I activate this \"When you deal damage to your opponent's Life\" effect twice?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can only activate this effect once."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-043",
        "title": "OP03-043 Gaimon",
        "question": "Q: Does this \"When you deal damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activate before a [Trigger] resulting from that damage?",
        "answer": "A: First, your opponent checks their Life in accordance with the damage dealt, and then this \"When you deal damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activates. After that, if the checked Life card has a [Trigger], your opponent can choose to activate it."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-047",
        "title": "OP03-047 Zeff",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to return 1 Character with a cost of 3 or less to the owner's hand and choose not to trash 2 cards from the top of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-047",
        "title": "OP03-047 Zeff",
        "question": "Q: Does this \"When this Character's attack deals damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activate before a [Trigger] resulting from that damage?",
        "answer": "A: First, your opponent checks their Life in accordance with the damage dealt, and then this \"When this Character's attack deals damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activates. After that, if the checked Life card has a [Trigger], your opponent can choose to activate it."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-051",
        "title": "OP03-051 Bell-mère",
        "question": "Q: Does this \"When this Character's attack deals damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activate before a [Trigger] resulting from that damage?",
        "answer": "A: First, your opponent checks their Life in accordance with the damage dealt, and then this \"When this Character's attack deals damage to your opponent's Life\" effect activates. After that, if the checked Life card has a [Trigger], your opponent can choose to activate it."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-054",
        "title": "OP03-054 Usopp's Rubber Band of Doom!!!",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Counter] effect to give my Leader +2000 power and choose not to trash 1 card from my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-054",
        "title": "OP03-054 Usopp's Rubber Band of Doom!!!",
        "question": "Q: To what extent is \"Draw 1 card and you may trash 1 card from the top of your deck.\" optional according to this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: If you choose to activate the Trigger, you must draw 1 card. You can then choose whether or not to trash 1 card from the top of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-055",
        "title": "OP03-055 Gum-Gum Giant Gavel",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Counter] effect to give my Leader +4000 power and choose not to trash 2 cards from my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-066",
        "title": "OP03-066 Paulie",
        "question": "Q: I had 7 DON!! cards on my field and activated this [On Play] effect to add a DON!! card from my DON!! deck. At this time, can I K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 4 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-070",
        "title": "OP03-070 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to trash a Character card with a cost of 4 or less?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-072",
        "title": "OP03-072 Gum-Gum Jet Gatling",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this card during the Counter Step and choose not to trash 1 card from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, none of your cards will gain +3000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-076",
        "title": "OP03-076 Rob Lucci",
        "question": "Q: During my turn in which I have not yet activated this [Your Turn] effect, when my opponent's Character was K.O.'d, I did not trash 2 cards from my hand and chose not to activate this [Your Turn] [Once Per Turn] effect. During that turn, can I activate this effect the next time my opponent's Character is K.O.'d?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-076",
        "title": "OP03-076 Rob Lucci",
        "question": "Q: When do I pay this \"trash 2 cards from your hand\" cost?",
        "answer": "A: Trash 2 cards from your hand when your opponent's Character is K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-078",
        "title": "OP03-078 Issho",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has 6 or more cards in their hand, who chooses which cards are trashed according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: The player who activated this [On Play] effect chooses 2 cards from their opponent's hand of face-down cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-078",
        "title": "OP03-078 Issho",
        "question": "Q: When I am to choose 2 cards from my opponent's hand, can my opponent rearrange the order of the cards in their hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-089",
        "title": "OP03-089 Brannew",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to add a card with the {Former Navy} or {Neo Navy} type to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-090",
        "title": "OP03-090 Blueno",
        "question": "Q: If this card and my Character with a type including \"CP\" and a cost of 4 or less are K.O.'d at the same time, can I use this [On K.O.] effect to play the card that was K.O.'d at the same time as this card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-091",
        "title": "OP03-091 Helmeppo",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [On Play] effect against my opponent's Character with a base cost of 6 when I had [OP02-121 Kuzan] on my field and the \"[Your Turn] Give all of your opponent's Characters −5 cost.\" effect was active. If [OP02-121 Kuzan] then leaves the field on that turn, does this Character's cost become 0?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, the cost becomes 0."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-094",
        "title": "OP03-094 Air Door",
        "question": "Q: Does the [On Play] effect of the Character played according to this [Main] effect activate prior to the carrying out of this [Main] effect's \"Then, trash the rest.\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, the [On Play] effect activates after the rest of the cards are trashed."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-095",
        "title": "OP03-095 Soap Sheep",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to give −4 cost to 1 of my opponent's Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-097",
        "title": "OP03-097 Six King Pistol",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this card during the Counter Step and choose not to trash 1 card from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, none of your cards will gain +3000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-099",
        "title": "OP03-099 Charlotte Katakuri",
        "question": "Q: Can this [When Attacking] effect give this Leader +1000 power even if there are no Life cards to look at?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-099",
        "title": "OP03-099 Charlotte Katakuri",
        "question": "Q: Can this [When Attacking] effect give this Leader +1000 power even if I look at a Life card that is placed face-up?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can. In this case, after looking at the face-up card, you can place it face-up at the top or bottom of the Life cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-100",
        "title": "OP03-100 Kingbaum",
        "question": "Q: If this 1 card is my only Life card, can I trash this card to pay the cost of the [Trigger] effect's \"You may trash 1 card from the top or bottom of your Life cards:\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-108",
        "title": "OP03-108 Charlotte Cracker",
        "question": "Q: I had 1 less Life card than my opponent when this Character gained [Double Attack] due to this [DON!! x1] effect and dealt 2 damage to my opponent's Leader. At this time, after my opponent checks their first Life card according to the first of the two damage dealt and the number of Life cards becomes the same, what happens to the next damage?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, after your opponent checks their first Life card, the [Double Attack] and +1000 power are lost. However, because the Leader has already taken 2 damage, the next damage is processed."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-112",
        "title": "OP03-112 Charlotte Pudding",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to add a [Sanji] without the {Big Mom Pirates} type to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-117",
        "title": "OP03-117 Napoleon",
        "question": "Q: Does \"your [Charlotte Linlin]\" refer to my Leader [Charlotte Linlin] or my Character [Charlotte Linlin] cards?",
        "answer": "A: It refers to both your Leader [Charlotte Linlin] and your Character [Charlotte Linlin] cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-118",
        "title": "OP03-118 Ikoku Sovereignty",
        "question": "Q: I have 1 Life card and take 2 damage from my opponent's [Double Attack]. This is the Life card I check for the first damage and I activate its [Trigger]. In this case, does adding 1 card to my Life cards according to this [Trigger] occur before processing the second damage of the [Double Attack]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. You will activate the [Trigger] before the second damage, add a card to your Life cards, and then process the second damage."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-119",
        "title": "OP03-119 Buzz Cut Mochi",
        "question": "Q: Does \"If you have less Life cards than your opponent,\" refer to the number of Life cards at the time this [Main] effect was activated?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it refers to the number of Life cards at that time."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-122",
        "title": "OP03-122 Sogeking",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character, activate the [On Play] effect and choose not to return a Character with a cost of 6 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, you must still draw 2 cards and trash 2 cards from your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP03-123",
        "title": "OP03-123 Charlotte Katakuri",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to add my Character to my Life?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-001",
        "title": "OP02-001 Edward.Newgate",
        "question": "Q: What happens according to the [End of Your Turn] effect if I have no Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Nothing will happen, and this [End of Your Turn] effect will not cause you to lose the game."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-002",
        "title": "OP02-002 Monkey.D.Garp",
        "question": "Q: If a Character's original cost is 8 or more, but it has been reduced to 7 or less by another effect, can I use this [Your Turn] effect to give it −1 cost?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-002",
        "title": "OP02-002 Monkey.D.Garp",
        "question": "Q: I gave 2 of my rested DON!! cards to this Leader using the [On Play] effect of [ST01-011 Brook]. At this time, can I give my opponent's Character −2 cost?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-004",
        "title": "OP02-004 Edward.Newgate",
        "question": "Q: If I have activated this [On Play] effect, can I pay the cost of \"You may add 1 card from the top of your Life cards to your hand:\" during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The effect cannot be activated because that activation cost cannot be paid."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-009",
        "title": "OP02-009 Squard",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if I have no Life cards, or cannot add a Life card to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You can use the [On Play] effect to reduce the power of your opponent's Character, but you cannot add a Life card to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-009",
        "title": "OP02-009 Squard",
        "question": "Q: When I play this Character, can I choose not to activate the [On Play] effect and not add a Life card to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The [On Play] effect is always activated, and you must add 1 Life card to your hand whenever possible."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-009",
        "title": "OP02-009 Squard",
        "question": "Q: If I do not use this [On Play] effect to give my opponent's Character −4000 power, can I choose not to add 1 card from the top of my Life cards to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Even if you do not give −4000 power, you must add 1 Life card to your hand whenever possible."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-013",
        "title": "OP02-013 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: Can this Character gain [Rush] if I do not give my opponent's Characters −3000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-013",
        "title": "OP02-013 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate the \"Give up to 2 of your opponent's Characters −3000 power during this turn\" effect if my Leader's type does not include \"Whitebeard Pirates\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, this Character cannot gain [Rush]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-013",
        "title": "OP02-013 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose the same Character twice and give that Character −6000 power according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-014",
        "title": "OP02-014 Whitey Bay",
        "question": "Q: Can I attack my opponent's rested Characters if this Character has gained this [DON!! x1] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-018",
        "title": "OP02-018 Marco",
        "question": "Q: This Character was given −2000 power by the [On Play] effect of [OP01-006 Otama] and K.O.'d. I then used its [On K.O.] effect to play this Character. At this time, is this Character played with −2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it is not. When this card is moved to a different area, it is treated as a different card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-023",
        "title": "OP02-023 You May Be a Fool...but I Still Love You",
        "question": "Q: Does \"If you have 3 or less Life cards\" mean if my current number of Life cards is 3 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it refers to the number of Life cards you currently have."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-023",
        "title": "OP02-023 You May Be a Fool...but I Still Love You",
        "question": "Q: If I have activated this [Main] effect, can I pay the cost of \"You may add 1 card from the top of your Life cards to your hand:\" during this turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The effect cannot be activated because that activation cost cannot be paid."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-023",
        "title": "OP02-023 You May Be a Fool...but I Still Love You",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Main] effect when I have 4 or more Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. You can activate the effect, but nothing will happen according to the [Main] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-024",
        "title": "OP02-024 Moby Dick",
        "question": "Q: Will this [Your Turn] effect give my Leader [Edward.Newgate] +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-024",
        "title": "OP02-024 Moby Dick",
        "question": "Q: Will this [Your Turn] effect give my Character [Edward.Newgate] +4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not. Your Character [Edward.Newgate] will gain +2000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-025",
        "title": "OP02-025 Kin'emon",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Activate: Main] when I had 0 Character cards. I then played a Character that does not have the {Land of Wano} type from my hand. Will the next {Land of Wano} type Character with a cost of 3 that I play from my hand have its cost reduced by 1?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-025",
        "title": "OP02-025 Kin'emon",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Activate: Main] when I had 0 Character cards. I then played a {Land of Wano} type Character with a cost of 1 from my hand. Will the next {Land of Wano} type Character with a cost of 3 that I play from my hand have its cost reduced by 1?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-025",
        "title": "OP02-025 Kin'emon",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Activate: Main] when I had 1 Character card. Can I then use the [On Play] effect of [OP01-047 Trafalgar Law] to play a {Land of Wano} type Character with a cost of 4 from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-025",
        "title": "OP02-025 Kin'emon",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Activate: Main] when I had 1 Character card. I then used the effect of [OP01-047 Trafalgar Law] to play a {Land of Wano} type Character with a cost of 3 from my hand without paying its cost. Will the next {Land of Wano} type Character that I play from my hand have its cost reduced by 1?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-025",
        "title": "OP02-025 Kin'emon",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Activate: Main] effect when I had 1 Character and then played a Character that is not a \"{Land of Wano} type Character card with a cost of 3 or more\" from my hand, so I now have 2 Characters on my field. If I then play a {Land of Wano} type Character card with a cost of 3 from my hand, will its cost be reduced by 1?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-026",
        "title": "OP02-026 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: I had 3 Characters and played a Character with no base effect from my hand. At this time, can use this [Once Per Turn] effect to set 2 of my DON!! cards as active?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-026",
        "title": "OP02-026 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: I had 0 Character cards and played a Character with no base effect from my hand. At this time, can I choose not to activate this [Once Per Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you must activate this effect whenever possible."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-026",
        "title": "OP02-026 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, I had 2 Character cards and played a Character with no base effect from my hand. At this time, can I use this [Once Per Turn] effect to set 2 of my DON!! cards as active?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-027",
        "title": "OP02-027 Inuarashi",
        "question": "Q: Does \"cannot be removed from the field by your opponent's effects\" also prevent this Character from being moved to my hand or deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. It will not be K.O.'d by effects, nor moved to your hand, deck or trash."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-027",
        "title": "OP02-027 Inuarashi",
        "question": "Q: Can I fulfill the \"If all of your DON!! cards are rested\" condition if there are DON!! cards given to my Characters or Leader?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-030",
        "title": "OP02-030 Kouzuki Oden",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On K.O.] effect to play a Character card with a cost of 2 or less?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can only play a Character with a cost of exactly 3."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-030",
        "title": "OP02-030 Kouzuki Oden",
        "question": "Q: If I do not play a Character card according to this [On K.O.] effect, can I choose not to shuffle my deck?",
        "answer": "A: If this Character is K.O.'d, the [On K.O.] effect is always activated, and the deck must be shuffled."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-031",
        "title": "OP02-031 Kouzuki Toki",
        "question": "Q: Can this Character gain [Blocker] according to this card's effect if I have a Character such as [OP02-042 Yamato] with \"Also treat this card's name as [Kouzuki Oden] according to the rules\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-035",
        "title": "OP02-035 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to play a Character with a cost of 2 or less?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can only play a Character with a cost of exactly 3."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-049",
        "title": "OP02-049 Emporio.Ivankov",
        "question": "Q: I had [OP02-065 Mr.3(Galdino)] on my field and its [End of Your Turn] effect reduced my hand to 0 cards. I then activated this card's [End of Your Turn] effect. In that case, can I draw 2 cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-049",
        "title": "OP02-049 Emporio.Ivankov",
        "question": "Q: If I have 0 cards in my hand, can I choose not to draw 2 cards according to this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you must draw 2 cards whenever possible."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-050",
        "title": "OP02-050 Inazuma",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is attacked and I activate a Counter from my hand, thereby reducing my hand to 1 or less cards, will this Character gain +2000 power according to this effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-051",
        "title": "OP02-051 Emporio.Ivankov",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to play a Character card if I have 3 or more cards in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-051",
        "title": "OP02-051 Emporio.Ivankov",
        "question": "Q: If I have 4 or more cards in my hand, do I need to trash some of them in order to have 3 cards in my hand for this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you do not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-051",
        "title": "OP02-051 Emporio.Ivankov",
        "question": "Q: If I have 2 or less cards in my hand, can I choose not to draw card(s) according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must draw cards until you have 3 cards whenever possible."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-059",
        "title": "OP02-059 Boa Hancock",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose to trash 0 cards according to the \"Then, trash up to 3 cards from your hand\" effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You can trash any number of cards in your hand from 0 to 3."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-062",
        "title": "OP02-062 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect and [When Attacking] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-062",
        "title": "OP02-062 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can I play or attack with this Character if I do not have 2 cards in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, you cannot activate its [On Play] effect or [When Attacking] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-062",
        "title": "OP02-062 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [On Play] or [When Attacking] effect, trash 2 cards from my hand, and then choose not to return 1 Character to the owner's hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. \"Return up to 1 Character\" means you can choose 0 Characters. In that case, this Character will still gain [Double Attack] during that turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-063",
        "title": "OP02-063 Mr.1(Daz.Bonez)",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to add an Event with a cost of 0 to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can only add an Event with a cost of exactly 1 to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-064",
        "title": "OP02-064 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is moved from the field to my hand or trash by a Counter or Trigger effect during the battle in which this [When Attacking] effect is activated, do I place it at the bottom of the owner's deck at the end of the battle?",
        "answer": "A: No, you do not. When this card is moved to a different area, it is treated as a different card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-064",
        "title": "OP02-064 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-064",
        "title": "OP02-064 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)",
        "question": "Q: The Character targeted by this Character's attack was placed at the bottom of the owner's deck according to this [When Attacking] effect. Do I then place this Character at the bottom of the owner's deck at the end of the battle?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you place it at the bottom of the owner's deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-065",
        "title": "OP02-065 Mr.3(Galdino)",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is active, can I trash 1 card from my hand to pay the activation cost of this [End of Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, nothing happens according to the effect that would set this Character as active."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-065",
        "title": "OP02-065 Mr.3(Galdino)",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader is [OP02-049 Emporio Ivankov], can I trash a card drawn according to that Leader's [End of Your Turn] effect by using this card's [End of Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-066",
        "title": "OP02-066 Impel Down All Stars",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader does not have the {Impel Down} type, can I trash a card from my hand to pay the activation cost of this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, you cannot draw 2 cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-067",
        "title": "OP02-067 Arabesque Brick Fist",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-068",
        "title": "OP02-068 Gum-Gum Rain",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Trigger] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-068",
        "title": "OP02-068 Gum-Gum Rain",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this card during the Counter Step and choose not to trash 1 card from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, 1 of your Leader or Character cards cannot gain +3000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-069",
        "title": "OP02-069 DEATH WINK",
        "question": "Q: I had 2 cards in my hand, including this card, and activated the [Counter] effect of this card in my hand. At this time, can I draw 1 card so that I have 2 cards in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-069",
        "title": "OP02-069 DEATH WINK",
        "question": "Q: If I have 3 or more cards in my hand, do I need to trash some of them in order to have 2 cards in my hand for this [Counter] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you do not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-069",
        "title": "OP02-069 DEATH WINK",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Trigger] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-070",
        "title": "OP02-070 New Kama Land",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose to trash 0 cards according to the \"Then, trash up to 3 cards from your hand\" effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You can trash any number of cards in your hand from 0 to 3."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-070",
        "title": "OP02-070 New Kama Land",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Activate: Main] effect if my Leader is not [Emporio Ivankov]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, this card is rested, but nothing happens according to the subsequent effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-071",
        "title": "OP02-071 Magellan",
        "question": "Q: Does \"When a DON!! card on your field is returned to your DON!! deck\" include when my opponent's DON!! card is returned to my opponent's DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-071",
        "title": "OP02-071 Magellan",
        "question": "Q: If 2 DON!! cards are returned to the DON!! deck at the same time according to \"DON!! −2\", what happens to this Leader's power?",
        "answer": "A: This Leader will gain +1000 Power."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-082",
        "title": "OP02-082 Byrnndi World",
        "question": "Q: Is the number written on this [Activate: Main] effect correct?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it is correct."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-085",
        "title": "OP02-085 Magellan",
        "question": "Q: Can my opponent return DON!! cards given to their Characters or Leader according to this [On Play] effect and [Opponent's Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-085",
        "title": "OP02-085 Magellan",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose which of my opponent's DON!! cards are returned according to this [On Play] effect and [Opponent's Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. Your opponent chooses which cards to return."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-089",
        "title": "OP02-089 Judgment of Hell",
        "question": "Q: Does \"up to a total of 2 of your opponent's Leader or Character cards\" allow me to choose 1 Leader and 1 Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-089",
        "title": "OP02-089 Judgment of Hell",
        "question": "Q: Does \"up to a total of 2 of your opponent's Leader or Character cards\" allow me to choose 2 Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-089",
        "title": "OP02-089 Judgment of Hell",
        "question": "Q: Does \"up to a total of 2 of your opponent's Leader or Character cards\" allow me to choose 1 Character twice and give it a total of −6000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-089",
        "title": "OP02-089 Judgment of Hell",
        "question": "Q: Can my opponent return a DON!! card given to their Character or Leader according to this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-089",
        "title": "OP02-089 Judgment of Hell",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose which of my opponent's DON!! cards is returned according to this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. Your opponent chooses which card to return."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-090",
        "title": "OP02-090 Hydra",
        "question": "Q: Can my opponent return a DON!! card given to their Character or Leader according to this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-090",
        "title": "OP02-090 Hydra",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose which of my opponent's DON!! cards is returned according to this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. Your opponent chooses which card to return."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-091",
        "title": "OP02-091 Venom Road",
        "question": "Q: Can my opponent return a DON!! card given to their Character or Leader according to this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-091",
        "title": "OP02-091 Venom Road",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose which of my opponent's DON!! cards is returned according to this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. Your opponent chooses which card to return."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-093",
        "title": "OP02-093 Smoker",
        "question": "Q: Will this Leader gain +1000 power if there is a Character with a cost of 0 that is not the Character given −1 cost by this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-093",
        "title": "OP02-093 Smoker",
        "question": "Q: If there are 2 Characters with a cost of 0, will this Leader gain +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-102",
        "title": "OP02-102 Smoker",
        "question": "Q: If there are 2 Characters with a cost of 0, will this Character gain +4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-110",
        "title": "OP02-110 Hina",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [On Block] effect to select an active Character of my opponent with [Rush], can it attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-110",
        "title": "OP02-110 Hina",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [On Block] effect to select a rested Character and that Character is then set as active by another effect, can that Character attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-110",
        "title": "OP02-110 Hina",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [On Block] effect to choose a Character that is attacking this Character, what happens to that attack?",
        "answer": "A: Since the attack has already been declared, the battle proceeds as usual."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-112",
        "title": "OP02-112 Bell-mère",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has no Characters, can 1 of my Leader or Character cards gain +1000 power according to this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-113",
        "title": "OP02-113 Helmeppo",
        "question": "Q: Will this Character gain +2000 power if there is a Character with a cost of 0 that is not the Character given −2 cost by this [When Attacking] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-113",
        "title": "OP02-113 Helmeppo",
        "question": "Q: If there are 2 Characters with a cost of 0, will this Character gain +4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-120",
        "title": "OP02-120 Uta",
        "question": "Q: Will a Character that is played after this [On Play] effect is activated gain +1000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-121",
        "title": "OP02-121 Kuzan",
        "question": "Q: Will this [Your Turn] effect give −5 cost to Character cards in my opponent's trash or hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not. When \"Character\" is written in card text, it refers only to Characters on the field."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-121",
        "title": "OP02-121 Kuzan",
        "question": "Q: My opponent's Character with a cost of 6 was reduced to a cost of 1 due to this [Your Turn] effect. Its cost was then further reduced to 0 according to the −2 cost effect of [OP02-106 Tsuru]. If this Character is then removed from the field, what will the cost of my opponent's Character be?",
        "answer": "A: In that case, the cost will become 4."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP02-121",
        "title": "OP02-121 Kuzan",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to choose a Character with a cost that has been reduced to 0 according to this [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-001",
        "title": "OP01-001 Roronoa Zoro",
        "question": "Q: If I give this Leader 2 DON!! cards, will this [Your Turn] effect grant all of my Characters +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-001",
        "title": "OP01-001 Roronoa Zoro",
        "question": "Q: I played a Character onto my field after giving this Leader 1 DON!! card. Will this Character also gain +1000 power according to this [Your Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-003",
        "title": "OP01-003 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can the Character attack again if this [Activate: Main] effect sets it as active?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-004",
        "title": "OP01-004 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: If this Character leaves the battle area due to an Event used by my opponent, can I draw a card according to this Character's effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-004",
        "title": "OP01-004 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent activates an Event's [Trigger], can I draw a card according to this Character's effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Activating a [Trigger] is not the same as activating an Event."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-004",
        "title": "OP01-004 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent activates an Event while this Character has a DON!! card given to it, can I choose not to draw a card?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-004",
        "title": "OP01-004 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: At what time does the effect which states \"when your opponent activates an Event\" activate?",
        "answer": "A: After the Event has been activated and its effect has been resolved."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-011",
        "title": "OP01-011 Gordon",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if I have no other cards in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, the [On Play] effect cannot be activated."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-014",
        "title": "OP01-014 Jinbe",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's [Blocker] effect if I don't have a Character card in my hand that I can play according to this [On Block] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-014",
        "title": "OP01-014 Jinbe",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Block] effect to play a Character card from my hand if I have 5 Characters in my Character area?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can.In that case, you will reveal the Character card that you will play, trash 1 of the Characters in your Character area, and then play your selected Character card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-016",
        "title": "OP01-016 Nami",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to add a non-red {Straw Hat Crew} type card that is not [Nami] to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-016",
        "title": "OP01-016 Nami",
        "question": "Q: What happens if there are no cards that I can add to my hand according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: You place all the cards you looked at from the top of your deck at the bottom of your deck in any order."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-016",
        "title": "OP01-016 Nami",
        "question": "Q: What happens according to this [On Play] effect if I have 4 or less cards in my deck?",
        "answer": "A: You will be able to look at all of the 4 or less cards in your deck.While looking at your deck, the number of cards in your deck will not be considered 0."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-016",
        "title": "OP01-016 Nami",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to add a [Nami] such as ST01-007 to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-020",
        "title": "OP01-020 Hyogoro",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's \"You may rest this Character:\" effect on the turn it is played?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-021",
        "title": "OP01-021 Franky",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this Character's [DON!! x1] effect to attack on the turn it is played?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-022",
        "title": "OP01-022 Brook",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to give 1 Character a total of −4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must choose up to 2 different Characters."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-024",
        "title": "OP01-024 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Does this [DON!! x2] effect mean this Character cannot be K.O.'d by the effects of <Strike> attribute Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, it can be K.O.'d by the effects of <Strike> attribute Characters. This effect means that this Character cannot be K.O.'d due to a battle result."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-026",
        "title": "OP01-026 Gum-Gum Fire-Fist Pistol Red Hawk",
        "question": "Q: What happens to a battle if the attacking Character is K.O.'d by this [Counter] effect?",
        "answer": "A: If the attacking Character or the Character being attacked is not on the field at the end of the Counter Step, the battle ends without proceeding to the Damage Step."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-026",
        "title": "OP01-026 Gum-Gum Fire-Fist Pistol Red Hawk",
        "question": "Q: If the attacking Character is K.O.'d by this [Counter] effect, can I then activate a [Counter]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-030",
        "title": "OP01-030 In Two Years!! At the Sabaody Archipelago!!",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to add a non-red {Straw Hat Crew} type Character card to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-030",
        "title": "OP01-030 In Two Years!! At the Sabaody Archipelago!!",
        "question": "Q: What happens if there are no cards that I can add to my hand according to this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: You place all the cards you looked at from the top of your deck at the bottom of your deck in any order."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-035",
        "title": "OP01-035 Okiku",
        "question": "Q: When attacking with this Character, can I make the Character rested by this Character's [When Attacking] effect the attack target?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The [When Attacking] effect activates and resolves after you select the attack target and declare your attack."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-038",
        "title": "OP01-038 Kanjuro",
        "question": "Q: When my opponent chooses a card from my hand, should my hand remain face-down?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. Your opponent is to choose a card without seeing the faces of the cards in your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-039",
        "title": "OP01-039 Killer",
        "question": "Q: Is this Character included in the count to determine \"If you have 3 or more Characters\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, this Character is included in the count."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-040",
        "title": "OP01-040 Kin'emon",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if my Leader is not [Kouzuki Oden]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Nothing will happen according to the [On Play] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-041",
        "title": "OP01-041 Kouzuki Momonosuke",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's \"You may rest this Character:\" effect on the turn it is played?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-041",
        "title": "OP01-041 Kouzuki Momonosuke",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to add a non-green {Land of Wano} type card to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-041",
        "title": "OP01-041 Kouzuki Momonosuke",
        "question": "Q: What happens if there are no cards that I can add to my hand according to this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: You place all the cards you looked at from the top of your deck at the bottom of your deck in any order."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-042",
        "title": "OP01-042 Komurasaki",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if my Leader is not [Kouzuki Oden]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You may choose whether or not to pay the cost of the [On Play] effect, but nothing will happen according to the effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-046",
        "title": "OP01-046 Denjiro",
        "question": "Q: Can I attack with this Character if my Leader is not [Kouzuki Oden]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Nothing will happen according to the [When Attacking] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-047",
        "title": "OP01-047 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: When I return a Character card to my hand with this [On Play] effect, can I then play that Character card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-049",
        "title": "OP01-049 Bepo",
        "question": "Q: If I have 5 Characters in my Character area when I use this [When Attacking] effect to play a Character, can I trash this Bepo?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, since the attacking Character will no longer be on the field, the battle will end without anything happening."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-051",
        "title": "OP01-051 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's \"You may rest this Character:\" effect on the turn it is played?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-051",
        "title": "OP01-051 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid",
        "question": "Q: What happens if my opponent has 2 [OP01-051 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid] on their field with this [Opponent's Turn] effect activated?",
        "answer": "A: You can attack any of your opponent's Characters with the card name [Eustass\"Captain\"Kid]."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-051",
        "title": "OP01-051 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to rest this Character if I have no Character cards with a cost of 3 or less in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-052",
        "title": "OP01-052 Raizo",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to draw a card if I have 2 rested Characters including this attacking Character?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-055",
        "title": "OP01-055 You Can Be My Samurai!!",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Main] effect by resting Characters played on this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-055",
        "title": "OP01-055 You Can Be My Samurai!!",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Event without resting 2 of my Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-057",
        "title": "OP01-057 Paradise Waterfall",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [Counter] effect to set as active a Character that is being attacked, will this invalidate the attack?",
        "answer": "A: No. The attack will not be invalidated because the attack target has already been set."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-057",
        "title": "OP01-057 Paradise Waterfall",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [Counter] effect to set a Character as active, can I activate that Character's [Blocker] during this battle?",
        "answer": "A: No. The [Blocker] cannot be activated because this battle's Block Step has already ended."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-059",
        "title": "OP01-059 BE-BENG!!",
        "question": "Q: Can the Character attack again if this [Main] effect sets it as active?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-060",
        "title": "OP01-060 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: If I reveal a card according to this [When Attacking] effect and then do not play it, should that card remain face-up?",
        "answer": "A: No. Return it to the top of your deck face-down."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-061",
        "title": "OP01-061 Kaido",
        "question": "Q: If I K.O. an opponent's Character with an effect such as \"DON!! −1:\", and simultaneously lose the DON!! card given to this Leader, is this [DON!! x1] effect activated?",
        "answer": "A: No. It is not activated because the [DON!! x1] condition was not met when your opponent's Character was K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-062",
        "title": "OP01-062 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: I activated an Event when I had 6 cards in my hand, and then activated another Event when I had 5 cards in my hand. I now have 4 cards in my hand. At this time, can I draw a card according to this [DON!! x1] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. You can draw 1 card because you have not yet drawn a card with this effect during this turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-062",
        "title": "OP01-062 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: I activated \"ST04-014 Lead Performer \"Disaster\"\" when I had 5 cards in my hand, reducing my hand to 4 cards. That Event's effect then increased my hand to 5 cards. At this time, can I draw a card according to this [DON!! x1] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. You cannot draw a card because you have 5 or more cards in your hand after activating the Event."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-062",
        "title": "OP01-062 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: Can I draw a card according to this [DON!! x1] effect if I activate the [Trigger] effect of one of my Events?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Activating a [Trigger] is not the same as activating an Event."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-062",
        "title": "OP01-062 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: At what time does the effect which states \"when you activates an Event\" activate?",
        "answer": "A: After the Event has been activated and its effect has been resolved."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-063",
        "title": "OP01-063 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's \"You may rest this Character:\" effect on the turn it is played?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-063",
        "title": "OP01-063 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: When choosing a card from my opponent's hand, should their hand remain face-down?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. Choose a card without seeing the faces of the cards in your opponent's hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-063",
        "title": "OP01-063 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: Can my opponent rearrange the order of the cards in their hand when I am selecting 1 card from their hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-063",
        "title": "OP01-063 Arlong",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has no cards in their hand, can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to reduce my opponent's Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can activate the effect, but nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-064",
        "title": "OP01-064 Alvida",
        "question": "Q: When this [When Attacking] effect is used to return a Character card, can that Character card's Counter be used during that battle?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-067",
        "title": "OP01-067 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: If this [DON!! x1] effect is activated multiple times, do the costs of Event cards become less than 0?",
        "answer": "A: No, they do not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-070",
        "title": "OP01-070 Dracule Mihawk",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to place my own Character at the bottom of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-071",
        "title": "OP01-071 Jinbe",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to place my own Character at the bottom of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-072",
        "title": "OP01-072 Smiley",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent uses a Counter against this Character's attack, and that effect increases or decreases the number of cards in my hand, will that change this Character's power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will. The battle result is determined by the amount of power on moving to the Damage Step."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-073",
        "title": "OP01-073 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: After looking at 5 cards from the top of my deck, can I place 1 card on the top and 4 cards on the bottom?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. After deciding the order in which you want to place the 5 cards, you must choose whether to return all 5 cards to the top or bottom of the deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-073",
        "title": "OP01-073 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: What happens according to this [On Play] effect if I have 4 or less cards in my deck?",
        "answer": "A: You will be able to look at all of the 4 or less cards in your deck.While looking at your deck, the number of cards in your deck will not be considered 0."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-075",
        "title": "OP01-075 Pacifista",
        "question": "Q: Does this card allow me to have 51 or more cards in my deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-077",
        "title": "OP01-077 Perona",
        "question": "Q: After looking at 5 cards from the top of my deck, can I place 1 card on the top and 4 cards on the bottom?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. After deciding the order in which you want to place the 5 cards, you must choose whether to return all 5 cards to the top or bottom of the deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-077",
        "title": "OP01-077 Perona",
        "question": "Q: What happens according to this [On Play] effect if I have 4 or less cards in my deck?",
        "answer": "A: You can activate this effect.While looking at your deck, the number of cards in your deck will not be considered 0."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-080",
        "title": "OP01-080 Miss Doublefinger(Zala)",
        "question": "Q: When this Character is K.O.'d, can I choose not to draw a card according to this [On K.O.] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. The effect always activates, and you must draw 1 card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-084",
        "title": "OP01-084 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to add a non-blue {Baroque Works} type Event to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-084",
        "title": "OP01-084 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)",
        "question": "Q: What happens according to this [When Attacking] effect if there aren't any {Baroque Works} type Event cards?",
        "answer": "A: You place all the cards you looked at from the top of your deck at the bottom of your deck in any order."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-085",
        "title": "OP01-085 Mr.3(Galdino)",
        "question": "Q: If I play this Character during my opponent's turn and activate this Character's [On Play] effect, when will the end of my opponent's next turn be?",
        "answer": "A: At the end of that turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-086",
        "title": "OP01-086 Overheat",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Counter] effect or [Trigger] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-086",
        "title": "OP01-086 Overheat",
        "question": "Q: What happens to a battle if this [Counter] effect is used to return the attacking Character or the Character being attacked to the owner's hand?",
        "answer": "A: If the attacking Character or the Character being attacked is not on the field at the end of the Counter Step, the battle ends without proceeding to the Damage Step."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-087",
        "title": "OP01-087 Officer Agents",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [Counter] effect to play a Character, can I activate that Character's [Blocker] during that battle?",
        "answer": "A: No. The [Blocker] cannot be activated because that battle's Block Step has already ended."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-088",
        "title": "OP01-088 Desert Spada",
        "question": "Q: After looking at 3 cards from the top of my deck, can I place 1 card on the top and 2 cards on the bottom?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. After deciding the order in which you want to place the 3 cards, you must choose whether to return all 3 cards to the top or bottom of the deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-088",
        "title": "OP01-088 Desert Spada",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect if I have 2 or less cards in my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can.While looking at your deck, the number of cards in your deck will not be considered 0."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-089",
        "title": "OP01-089 Crescent Cutlass",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Event if my Leader does not have the {The Seven Warlords of the Sea} type?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. You can activate the Event, but nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-089",
        "title": "OP01-089 Crescent Cutlass",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Counter] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-091",
        "title": "OP01-091 King",
        "question": "Q: Does \"If you have 10 DON!! cards on your field\" mean 10 DON!! cards including any given to my Leader or Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. All DON!! cards in your Leader area, Character area, Stage area, and cost area are counted."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-093",
        "title": "OP01-093 Ulti",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if I have no cards in my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, you may choose whether or not to pay the cost of the [On Play] effect, but nothing will happen according to the effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-093",
        "title": "OP01-093 Ulti",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if I can't pay the ① cost of the [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-094",
        "title": "OP01-094 Kaido",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if my Leader does not have the {Animal Kingdom Pirates} type?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You may choose whether or not to pay the cost of the [On Play] effect, but nothing will happen according to the effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-094",
        "title": "OP01-094 Kaido",
        "question": "Q: What Character does \"this Character\" refer to in \"K.O. all Characters other than this Character.\" according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: It refers only to the 1 card that activated this effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-095",
        "title": "OP01-095 Kyoshirou",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if I do not have 8 or more DON!! cards on my field?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-095",
        "title": "OP01-095 Kyoshirou",
        "question": "Q: Does \"If you have 8 or more DON!! cards on your field\" mean 8 DON!! cards including any given to my Leader or Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. All DON!! cards in your Leader area, Character area, Stage area, and cost area are counted."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-096",
        "title": "OP01-096 King",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect if there is only one Character that can be K.O.'d by this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-101",
        "title": "OP01-101 Sasaki",
        "question": "Q: Can I attack with this Character if I have no cards in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-101",
        "title": "OP01-101 Sasaki",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [When Attacking] effect to trash a card from my hand if I have no cards in my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-102",
        "title": "OP01-102 Jack",
        "question": "Q: When attacking with this Character, can I choose not to return a DON!! card to my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, you cannot activate the [When Attacking] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-105",
        "title": "OP01-105 Bao Huang",
        "question": "Q: When choosing cards from my opponent's hand, should their hand remain face-down?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. Choose the cards without seeing the faces of the cards in your opponent's hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-105",
        "title": "OP01-105 Bao Huang",
        "question": "Q: Can my opponent rearrange the order of the cards in their hand when I am selecting 2 cards from their hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-105",
        "title": "OP01-105 Bao Huang",
        "question": "Q: When choosing 2 cards from my opponent's hand, should the first card I select be revealed before I select a second card?",
        "answer": "A: No. The 2 cards are to be chosen at the same time, and then revealed at the same time."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-108",
        "title": "OP01-108 Hitokiri Kamazo",
        "question": "Q: When this Character is K.O.'d, can I choose not to K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters according to this [On K.O.] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-109",
        "title": "OP01-109 Who's.Who",
        "question": "Q: Does \"If you have 8 or more DON!! cards on your field\" mean 8 DON!! cards including any given to my Leader or Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. All DON!! cards in your Leader area, Character area, Stage area, and cost area are counted."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-112",
        "title": "OP01-112 Page One",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's [Activate: Main] effect to attack on the turn it is played?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-113",
        "title": "OP01-113 Holedem",
        "question": "Q: When this Character is K.O.'d, can I choose not to add a DON!! card according to this [On K.O.] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-114",
        "title": "OP01-114 X.Drake",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if my opponent has no cards in their hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You may choose whether or not to pay the cost of the [On Play] effect, but nothing will happen according to the effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-114",
        "title": "OP01-114 X.Drake",
        "question": "Q: Does my opponent choose which card they trash according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. The owner of the hand, your opponent, chooses."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-115",
        "title": "OP01-115 Elephant's Marchoo",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Main] effect if I have no cards in my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-116",
        "title": "OP01-116 Artificial Devil Fruit SMILE",
        "question": "Q: What happens if there are no Character cards that I can play according to this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: You place all the cards you looked at from the top of your deck at the bottom of your deck in any order."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-116",
        "title": "OP01-116 Artificial Devil Fruit SMILE",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [Trigger] effect to play a card with an [On Play] effect, will the [On Play] effect activate?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the effect will activate."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-118",
        "title": "OP01-118 Ulti-Mortar",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose not to draw a card according to this [Counter] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. According to this effect, you must always draw 1 card."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-119",
        "title": "OP01-119 Thunder Bagua",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Counter] effect if I have no cards in my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-044",
        "title": "OP01-044 Shachi",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to play \"ST10-008 Shachi & Penguin\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. \"Shachi & Penguin\" is not the same card name as \"Penguin\"."
    },
    {
        "id": "OP01-050",
        "title": "OP01-050 Penguin",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to play \"ST10-008 Shachi & Penguin\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. \"Shachi & Penguin\" is not the same card name as \"Shachi\"."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST21-003",
        "title": "ST21-003 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: After the Character selected by this [On Play] effect finishes attacking, if another Character or Leader attacks during the same turn, can my opponent activate [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST21-015",
        "title": "ST21-015 Roronoa Zoro",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On K.O.] effect to play other [Roronoa Zoro] cards, such as \"OP01-025 Roronoa Zoro\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST21-015",
        "title": "ST21-015 Roronoa Zoro",
        "question": "Q: During my opponent's turn, I played \"OP09-013 Yasopp\" using this [On K.O.] effect, and activated its \"[On Play] Up to 1 of your Leader gains +1000 power until the end of your opponent's next turn.\" effect. In this case, how long will my Leader gain +1000 power for?",
        "answer": "A: Your Leader will gain +1000 power until the end of your opponent's current turn. When an effect that reads \"until the end of your opponent's next turn.\" occurs during your opponent's turn, that effect will end at the end of their current turn."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST21-017",
        "title": "ST21-017 Gum-Gum Mole Pistol",
        "question": "Q: When activating this [Main] effect, can I choose to give −5000 power to one Character, and then choose to K.O. a different Character with 2000 power or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST20-001",
        "title": "ST20-001 Charlotte Katakuri",
        "question": "Q: If the card at the top of my Life cards is already face-up, can I still use this [Activate: Main] effect to give up to 1 rested DON!! card to my Leader or 1 of my Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST20-002",
        "title": "ST20-002 Charlotte Cracker",
        "question": "Q: If I have no Life cards when this Character would be K.O.'d by an effect, can I still prevent this Character from being K.O.'d instead?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST20-005",
        "title": "ST20-005 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [On Play] effect and my opponent chooses \"Your opponent trashes 2 cards from their hand\", which player trashes 2 cards from their hand?",
        "answer": "A: The player who did not activate this [On Play] effect will choose 2 cards from their hand and place them in their trash."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST20-005",
        "title": "ST20-005 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [On Play] effect and my opponent chooses \"Trash 1 card from the top of your opponent's Life cards\", which player trashes 1 card from their Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: The player who did not activate this [On Play] effect will trash 1 card from the top of their Life cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST20-005",
        "title": "ST20-005 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [On Play] effect when my opponent had no Life cards, and trashed 1 card from my hand. Can my opponent still choose \"Trash 1 card from the top of your opponent's Life cards\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can. In this case, nothing will happen as they have no Life cards to trash."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST19-003",
        "title": "ST19-003 Tashigi",
        "question": "Q: Can a Character's [On K.O.] effect be activated when it is trashed by this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST19-003",
        "title": "ST19-003 Tashigi",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader is not [Smoker], can I still use this [Activate: Main] effect to trash up to 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 0?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST19-004",
        "title": "ST19-004 Hina",
        "question": "Q: If I have no cards in my trash, can I still use this [Activate: Main] effect to give up to 1 rested DON!! card to my Leader or 1 of my Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST19-005",
        "title": "ST19-005 Monkey.D.Garp",
        "question": "Q: If I have no cards in my trash, can I still use this [Activate: Main] effect to give up to 1 of my opponent's Characters −1 cost during this turn?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST18-002",
        "title": "ST18-002 O-Nami",
        "question": "Q: If I have 0 cards in my hand but 8 or more DON!! cards on my field, can I use this [On Play] effect to draw 2 cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST17-001",
        "title": "ST17-001 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [On Play] effect to reveal 1 card from the top of my deck, and that card is a {The Seven Warlords of the Sea} type card, what happens to the revealed card?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, the revealed card will count as one of the 2 cards you draw from your deck, and then you will place 1 card from your hand at the top of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST17-001",
        "title": "ST17-001 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [On Play] effect to reveal 1 card from the top of my deck, and that card is not a {The Seven Warlords of the Sea} type card, what happens?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, the revealed card is returned face-down to the top of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST17-002",
        "title": "ST17-002 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to return 1 of my Characters to my hand even if my Leader does not have the {The Seven Warlords of the Sea} type?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, you cannot return 1 of your opponent's Characters with a cost of 4 or less to their hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST16-002",
        "title": "ST16-002 Gordon",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Your Opponent's Attack] effect to trash 2 {Music} type cards from my hand to give 2 of my Characters +1000 power each?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST16-003",
        "title": "ST16-003 Charlotte Katakuri",
        "question": "Q: If I have 6 rested cards, and those rested cards include this Character, does this Character gain +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will gain +2000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST15-004",
        "title": "ST15-004 Thatch",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader's type includes \"Whitebeard Pirates\" but I have no Life cards or any Life cards to add to my hand, can I play this card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In this case, you can use the [On Play] effect to lower the power of 1 of your opponent's Characters, but you will not be able to add a Life card to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST15-004",
        "title": "ST15-004 Thatch",
        "question": "Q: My Leader is a Leader with the type \"Whitebeard Pirates\". If this Character's [On Play] effect does not give 1 of my opponent's Characters −2000 power, can I choose not to add 1 card from the top of my Life cards to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. Even if you do not give 1 of your opponent's Characters −2000 power, you must add 1 card from your Life cards to your hand if possible."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-001",
        "title": "ST14-001 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Does this [DON!! x1] effect give +1 cost to Character cards in my hand or trash?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not. This effect only gives +1 cost to Characters on your field."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-001",
        "title": "ST14-001 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: My Leader is \"ST14-001 Monkey.D.Luffy\" and has a DON!! card given to it, so during my opponent's turn, because I have 1 Character with a cost of 8 on the field, my Leader has +6000 power according to this [DON!! x1] effect. During this same turn, if I no longer have a Character with a cost of 8 or more on the field, does my Leader's power become 5000?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it becomes 5000."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-002",
        "title": "ST14-002 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: If this Character has a cost of 8 or more, can I use this Character's [When Attacking] effect to K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 4 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-003",
        "title": "ST14-003 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: If this Character has a cost of 6 or more, can I use this Character's [On Play] effect to K.O. 1 of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 5 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-003",
        "title": "ST14-003 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: My Leader is \"ST14-001 Monkey.D.Luffy\" and has a DON!! card given to it, and I have no Characters on the field. If I play \"ST14-003 Sanji\" at this time, can I use Sanji's [On Play] effect to K.O. one of my opponent's Characters with a cost of 5 or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-007",
        "title": "ST14-007 Nico Robin",
        "question": "Q: If this Character has a cost of 8 or more, can I use this Character's [On Play]/[When Attacking] effect to give 1 of my opponent's Characters −5 cost?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-009",
        "title": "ST14-009 Franky",
        "question": "Q: If this Character has a cost of 6 or more, does that mean this Character cannot be K.O.'d by my opponent's card effects and gains +2000 power, according to this [Opponent's Turn] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-012",
        "title": "ST14-012 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If this Character has a cost of 10 or more, does this Character gain [Rush]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST14-017",
        "title": "ST14-017 Thousand Sunny",
        "question": "Q: Does this effect give +1 cost to Character cards in my hand or trash?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not. This effect only gives +1 cost to black {Straw Hat Crew} type Characters on your field."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-001",
        "title": "ST13-001 Sabo",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to add my Character with a base power of 6000 that has had its power raised to 7000 or more by DON!! cards etc. to the top of my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-002",
        "title": "ST13-002 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: Does this [End of Your Turn] effect require me to trash cards that have been placed face-up in my Life area by an effect etc. other than this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you must trash them."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-003",
        "title": "ST13-003 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If this card is my Leader, can I activate the [Trigger] effects of my face-up Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-003",
        "title": "ST13-003 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If this card is my Leader, can I activate and resolve the effect of \"ST13-012 Makino\" (\"[On Play] You may add 1 card from the top or bottom of your Life cards to your hand: Look at all of your Life cards and place them back in your Life area in any order.\") by placing 1 of my face-up Life cards at the bottom of my deck instead of adding it to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: You can use this [On Play] effect to place 1 face-up Life card at the bottom of your deck instead of adding it to your hand, but because you have not paid the cost \"You may add 1 card from the top or bottom of your Life cards to your hand:\", nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-003",
        "title": "ST13-003 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If this card is my Leader, and I have 1 face-up Life card, and my opponent has 1 Life card, can I activate the \"• If your opponent has 1 Life card, deal 1 damage to your opponent. Then, add 1 card from the top of your Life cards to your hand.\" effect of \"OP06-116 Reject\"?",
        "answer": "A: You will deal 1 damage to your opponent and then put your 1 Life card at the bottom of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-003",
        "title": "ST13-003 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to add 1 card from my hand and 1 card from my trash (a total of 2 cards) to the top of my Life cards face-up?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-004",
        "title": "ST13-004 Edward.Newgate",
        "question": "Q: When I place face-up Life cards back in my Life area according to this [On Play] effect, do I place them face-down?",
        "answer": "A: No. You must place face-up Life cards face-up, and face-down Life cards face-down."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-004",
        "title": "ST13-004 Edward.Newgate",
        "question": "Q: When I use this [On Play] effect to place a face-up Life card on top of my deck, do I place that card face-down?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the card should be placed face-down on top of your deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-009",
        "title": "ST13-009 Shanks",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to turn any face-up card in my Life area face-down, regardless of its position in the area?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-011",
        "title": "ST13-011 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: If I play this card when I have 2 Life cards, and then I have 3 Life cards, can this Character still attack on this turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can attack."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-012",
        "title": "ST13-012 Makino",
        "question": "Q: When I look at all my Life cards and place them back in any order according to this [On Play] effect, do I place the face-up Life cards face-down?",
        "answer": "A: No. You must place face-up Life cards face-up, and face-down Life cards face-down."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-016",
        "title": "ST13-016 Yamato",
        "question": "Q: When I place face-up Life cards back in my Life area according to this [On Play] effect, do I place them face-down?",
        "answer": "A: No. You must place face-up Life cards face-up, and face-down Life cards face-down."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST13-017",
        "title": "ST13-017 Flame Dragon King",
        "question": "Q: When I look at all my Life cards and place them back in any order according to this [On Play] effect, do I place the face-up Life cards face-down?",
        "answer": "A: No. You must place face-up Life cards face-up, and face-down Life cards face-down."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST12-001",
        "title": "ST12-001 Roronoa Zoro & Sanji",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this Leader's [When Attacking] effect to set as active a Character with a base power of 7000 that has had its power increased to 8000 by a DON!! card given to it?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST12-003",
        "title": "ST12-003 Dracule Mihawk",
        "question": "Q: If I play this Character and I now have 3 Characters including this Character, can I use this [On Play] effect to play 1 Character card?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST12-011",
        "title": "ST12-011 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [When Attacking] effect when I have 5 cards in my hand, and then the number of cards in my hand becomes 6 or more before the start of my next turn, will this Character still have +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, this Character will still have +2000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST12-011",
        "title": "ST12-011 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [When Attacking] effect twice during one turn, can this Character gain a total of +4000 power?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST12-010",
        "title": "ST12-010 Emporio.Ivankov",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this Character's [On Play] effect to play a Character with a cost of 2 from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot.The only card you can play using this Character's [On Play] effect is the card revealed according to this Character's effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST12-010",
        "title": "ST12-010 Emporio.Ivankov",
        "question": "Q: Does \"place the rest at the top or bottom of your deck\" in this Character's [On Play] effect refer to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No.This Character's \"place the rest at the top or bottom of your deck\" refers to the action taken with the card revealed according to this Character's effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST11-001",
        "title": "ST11-001 Uta",
        "question": "Q: What happens regarding the \"place the rest at the bottom of your deck\" effect if I use this [When Attacking] effect to add 1 {FILM} type card to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: In this case, nothing will happen after you add the 1 {FILM} type card to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST11-004",
        "title": "ST11-004 New Genesis",
        "question": "Q: If I don't use this [Main] effect to add 1 {FILM} type card other than [New Genesis] to my hand, can I still set 1 of my DON!! cards as active?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-001",
        "title": "ST10-001 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: Can I still use this [Activate: Main] effect to play up to 1 Character card with a cost of 4 or less from my hand if my opponent has no Characters with 3000 power or less?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-001",
        "title": "ST10-001 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to place up to 1 of my opponent's Characters with 3000 power or less at the bottom of the owner's deck without playing 1 Character card with a cost of 4 or less from my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-002",
        "title": "ST10-002 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: If it is the start of the game and I have no DON!! cards on my field, can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to add up to 1 DON!! card from my DON!! deck and set it as active?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-002",
        "title": "ST10-002 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: What does \"you have 0 DON!! cards on your field\" mean?",
        "answer": "A: It means you have no DON!! cards either in your cost area or on your field."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-004",
        "title": "ST10-004 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: I played this Character and gained [Rush] from this [On Play] effect, and then the situation changed during that turn such that my opponent no longer has a Character with 5000 or more power on their field. Can this Character still attack during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-006",
        "title": "ST10-006 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Once Per Turn] effect to K.O. a Character other than my opponent's Character that activated [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-006",
        "title": "ST10-006 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: I attacked with this Character and my opponent activated [Blocker]. If I use this Character's [Once Per Turn] effect to K.O. my opponent's Character that activated [Blocker], what happens to this Character's attack?",
        "answer": "A: The battle will end without moving to the Counter Step."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-007",
        "title": "ST10-007 Killer",
        "question": "Q: Does this [Your Turn] effect activate if a DON!! card on my field is returned to my DON!! deck by the effect of an opponent's card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-010",
        "title": "ST10-010 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has 7 or more cards in their hand, which player chooses the cards to be trashed according to this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: The player who activated this [On Play] effect chooses 2 cards from their opponent's hand face-down."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-011",
        "title": "ST10-011 Heat",
        "question": "Q: Does this [Your Turn] effect activate if a DON!! card on my field is returned to my DON!! deck by the effect of an opponent's card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-014",
        "title": "ST10-014 Wire",
        "question": "Q: Does this [Once Per Turn] effect activate if a DON!! card on my field is returned to my DON!! deck by the effect of an opponent's card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-014",
        "title": "ST10-014 Wire",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose not to draw a card according to this [Once Per Turn] effect when a DON!! card on my field is returned to my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must draw 1 card and trash 1 card from your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-016",
        "title": "ST10-016 Gum-Gum Kong Gatling",
        "question": "Q: Until when is this [Trigger] (\"until the end of your next turn\") effective?",
        "answer": "A: It is effective until it has become your turn again and that turn has concluded."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST10-001",
        "title": "ST10-001 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: I have no \"Monkey.D.Luffy\" on my field when I use this Leader's [Activate: Main] effect to select my opponent's \"OP05-100 Enel\" with 3000 power or less, and play a \"Monkey.D.Luffy\" with a cost of 4 or less from my hand. Can my opponent use the [Once Per Turn] effect of \"OP05-100 Enel\" to trash 1 card from the top of their Life cards instead of placing this \"Enel\" at the bottom of their deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST09-001",
        "title": "ST09-001 Yamato",
        "question": "Q: I have 3 Life cards when this Leader with a DON!! card given to it is attacked by a Character with 5000 power and [Double Attack]. At this time, if I have 2 Life cards after I take the first damage, what happens when I take the next damage?",
        "answer": "A: After the first damage reduces your Life cards to 2, this Leader's power will become 6000 according to this [Opponent's Turn] effect. However, the second damage will still be processed."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST09-002",
        "title": "ST09-002 Uzuki Tempura",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this card's Trigger, can I decide not to add this card to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST09-008",
        "title": "ST09-008 Shimotsuki Ushimaru",
        "question": "Q: If the card added from my Life cards to my hand by this [When Attacking] effect is a \"yellow {Land of Wano} type Character card with a cost of 4 or less\", can I use this effect to play that card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST09-009",
        "title": "ST09-009 Fugetsu Omusubi",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this card's Trigger, can I decide not to add this card to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST09-010",
        "title": "ST09-010 Portgas.D.Ace",
        "question": "Q: If I have no Life cards when this Character would be K.O.'d, can I still trash 1 card from the top or bottom of my Life cards instead?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST08-001",
        "title": "ST08-001 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: When 2 Characters are K.O.'d at the same time during my turn, can I use this [Your Turn] effect to give 2 DON!! cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. You can give DON!! cards up to the number of Characters K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST08-005",
        "title": "ST08-005 Shanks",
        "question": "Q: After I activate this [On Play] effect and trash 1 card from my hand, can I choose whether or not to K.O. my Characters with a cost of 1 or less?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This effect will K.O. all of your and your opponent's Characters with a cost of 1 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST08-013",
        "title": "ST08-013 Mr.2.Bon.Kurei(Bentham)",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is attacked by my opponent's Character, loses the battle and is K.O.'d, this Character will be in my trash at the end of that battle. Can I still activate the [DON!! x1] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-001",
        "title": "ST07-001 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: If I have 3 Life cards, can I use this [When Attacking] effect to add 1 card from the top or bottom of my Life cards to my hand, and add 1 card from my hand to the top of my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-001",
        "title": "ST07-001 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [When Attacking] effect if I have 4 or more Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, nothing will happen after you add 1 card from the top or bottom of your Life cards to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-001",
        "title": "ST07-001 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [When Attacking] effect if I have 0 Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-010",
        "title": "ST07-010 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [On Play] effect and my opponent chooses \"• Trash 1 card from the top of your opponent's Life cards.\", which player's Life card is trashed?",
        "answer": "A: The card at the top of the Life cards of the player who did not activate this [On Play] effect is trashed."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-010",
        "title": "ST07-010 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [On Play] effect and my opponent chooses \"• Add 1 card from the top of your deck to the top of your Life cards.\", which player adds a card to their Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: The card at the top of the deck of the player who activated this [On Play] effect is added to the top of that player's Life cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-010",
        "title": "ST07-010 Charlotte Linlin",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [On Play] effect when my opponent had 0 Life cards. Can my opponent choose \"• Trash 1 card from the top of your opponent's Life cards.\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can. In this case, nothing will happen because there is no Life card that can be trashed."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-011",
        "title": "ST07-011 Zeus",
        "question": "Q: Does \"your [Charlotte Linlin]\" refer to my Leader [Charlotte Linlin] or my Character [Charlotte Linlin] cards?",
        "answer": "A: It refers to both your Leader [Charlotte Linlin] and your Character [Charlotte Linlin] cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-013",
        "title": "ST07-013 Prometheus",
        "question": "Q: Does \"your [Charlotte Linlin]\" refer to my Leader [Charlotte Linlin] or my Character [Charlotte Linlin] cards?",
        "answer": "A: It refers to both your Leader [Charlotte Linlin] and your Character [Charlotte Linlin] cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-015",
        "title": "ST07-015 Soul Pocus",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [Main] effect and my opponent chooses \"• Trash 1 card from the top of your opponent's Life cards.\", which player's Life card is trashed?",
        "answer": "A: The card at the top of the Life cards of the player who did not activate this [Main] effect is trashed."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-015",
        "title": "ST07-015 Soul Pocus",
        "question": "Q: If I activate this [Main] effect and my opponent chooses \"• Add 1 card from the top of your deck to the top of your Life cards.\", which player adds a card to their Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: The card at the top of the deck of the player who activated this [Main] effect is added to the top of that player's Life cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-015",
        "title": "ST07-015 Soul Pocus",
        "question": "Q: I activated this [Main] effect when my opponent had 0 Life cards. Can my opponent choose \"• Trash 1 card from the top of your opponent's Life cards.\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, they can. In this case, nothing will happen because there is no Life card that can be trashed."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-015",
        "title": "ST07-015 Soul Pocus",
        "question": "Q: I have 1 Life card and take 2 damage from my opponent's [Double Attack]. This is the Life card I check for the first damage and I activate its [Trigger]. In this case, does adding 1 card to my Life cards according to this [Trigger] occur before processing the second damage of the [Double Attack]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. You will activate the [Trigger] before the second damage, add a card to your Life cards, and then process the second damage."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-017",
        "title": "ST07-017 Queen Mama Chanter",
        "question": "Q: I used this [Activate: Main] effect to rest this Stage and add 1 of my Life cards to my hand. At this time, can I choose not to add 1 of my Characters with a cost of 3 to my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-017",
        "title": "ST07-017 Queen Mama Chanter",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to add my Character with a cost of 2 or less to my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can only add a Character with a cost of exactly 3 to your Life cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST07-017",
        "title": "ST07-017 Queen Mama Chanter",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to add a Character card from my hand to my Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. When included in card text, \"Character\" refers only to Characters on the field."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST06-002",
        "title": "ST06-002 Koby",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if I have no cards in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, you cannot activate its [On Play] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST06-004",
        "title": "ST06-004 Smoker",
        "question": "Q: This Character gained [Double Attack] according to its [DON!! x1] effect and is attacking. During this battle, the Character with a cost of 0 was removed from the field by an Event's [Counter] effect. How much damage will this Character deal?",
        "answer": "A: If there is no Character with a cost of 0 on the field before the Damage Step, this Character loses [Double Attack] and deals 1 damage to the Leader."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST06-004",
        "title": "ST06-004 Smoker",
        "question": "Q: Will this Character be K.O.'d by the [On Play] effect of [OP01-094 Kaido]?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST06-012",
        "title": "ST06-012 Monkey.D.Garp",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to rest this Character without trashing a card from my hand, or trash a card from my hand without resting this Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot.All instructions specified before a colon are activation costs. Activation costs cannot be paid only in part.If a part or all of the activation cost cannot be paid, then the effect cannot be activated."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST06-015",
        "title": "ST06-015 Great Eruption",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Trigger] effect if my opponent has no cards in their hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, nothing will happen according to the effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST06-015",
        "title": "ST06-015 Great Eruption",
        "question": "Q: Can I select the target to give −2 cost after drawing a card according to this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. Effects are processed in order, starting from the first effect written on the card."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST06-016",
        "title": "ST06-016 White Out",
        "question": "Q: During the turn this [Trigger] effect is activated, does the effect preventing K.O. also apply to Characters I play afterwards?",
        "answer": "A: No, it does not. The effect preventing K.O. only applies to Characters that have been played when this [Trigger] effect is activated."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST06-017",
        "title": "ST06-017 Navy HQ",
        "question": "Q: Can I use these [On Play] and [Activate: Main] effects to reduce the costs of different Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST05-001",
        "title": "ST05-001 Shanks",
        "question": "Q: Can this [Activate: Main] effect give this Leader +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST05-005",
        "title": "ST05-005 Carina",
        "question": "Q: If I have 1 card in my DON!! deck, can I add a DON!! card to the cost area with this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST05-008",
        "title": "ST05-008 Shiki",
        "question": "Q: Does \"If you have 8 or more DON!! cards on your field\" mean 8 DON!! cards including any given to my Leader or Characters?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. All DON!! cards in your Leader area, Character area, Stage area, and cost area are counted."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST05-010",
        "title": "ST05-010 Zephyr",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is attacked twice by <Strike> attribute Characters, will it gain a total of +6000 power during that turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it will gain +6000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST05-011",
        "title": "ST05-011 Douglas Bullet",
        "question": "Q: If my opponent has no Characters on their field, can this Character gain [Double Attack] according to this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST05-017",
        "title": "ST05-017 Union Armada",
        "question": "Q: Does this [Counter] effect mean that the Character selected will not be K.O.'d, whether by an effect or in battle?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. The Character will not be K.O.'d by an effect or in battle."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-001",
        "title": "ST04-001 Kaido",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this effect to win the game if my opponent has no Life cards?",
        "answer": "A: No. You can activate this effect, but if your opponent has no Life cards, nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-002",
        "title": "ST04-002 Ulti",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character card if I have no cards in my hand that I can play with this [On Play] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-003",
        "title": "ST04-003 Kaido",
        "question": "Q: Can I gain [Rush] using this [On Play] effect if there is no Character I can K.O.?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. When a card's text states \"up to\" a specified number of cards, you can choose 0 cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-008",
        "title": "ST04-008 Jack",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect if I have no cards in my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. Nothing will happen after you trash 1 card from your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-008",
        "title": "ST04-008 Jack",
        "question": "Q: Can I play this Character if I have no cards in my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, you cannot activate its [On Play] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-010",
        "title": "ST04-010 Who's.Who",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this Character card's [Trigger] effect to play this card if I have no DON!! cards that I can return to my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, because you don't have enough DON!! cards, you cannot activate the [On Play] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-014",
        "title": "ST04-014 Lead Performer \"Disaster\"",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose to only carry out the \"add up to 1 DON!! card from your DON!! deck and set it as active\" part of this effect?",
        "answer": "A: No. According to this effect, you must also draw 1 card whenever possible."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-014",
        "title": "ST04-014 Lead Performer \"Disaster\"",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect if I have no cards in my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-015",
        "title": "ST04-015 Brachio Bomber",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect if I have no cards in my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-016",
        "title": "ST04-016 Blast Breath",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this card without paying the DON!! −1?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. You can activate the card, but nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-017",
        "title": "ST04-017 Onigashima Island",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Activate: Main] effect if my Leader does not have the {Animal Kingdom Pirates} type?",
        "answer": "A: Yes. You can activate the effect, but nothing will happen."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST04-017",
        "title": "ST04-017 Onigashima Island",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect if I have no cards in my DON!! deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-001",
        "title": "ST03-001 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-003",
        "title": "ST03-003 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: What happens to a battle if this [On Block] effect is used to place the attacking Character at the bottom of the owner's deck?",
        "answer": "A: If the attacking Character is not on the field, the battle ends without anything happening."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-003",
        "title": "ST03-003 Crocodile",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Block] effect to place my own Character at the bottom of my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-004",
        "title": "ST03-004 Gecko Moria",
        "question": "Q: Can I add a card with the name [Gecko Moria] to my hand so long as it isn't \"ST03-004 Gecko Moria\"?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. This effect does not allow you to add any cards with the name [Gecko Moria] to your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-005",
        "title": "ST03-005 Dracule Mihawk",
        "question": "Q: If I have 1 or less cards in my deck, can I use this Character to attack if it has a DON!! card given to it?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. However, since the [When Attacking] effect is always activated and requires a player to draw 2 cards whenever possible, if the deck is reduced to 0 cards as a result, the player with 0 cards in their deck will lose the game."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-007",
        "title": "ST03-007 Sentomaru",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect even if I have no [Pacifista] cards in my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. After looking at your deck, proceed to shuffling your deck without playing any cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-009",
        "title": "ST03-009 Donquixote Doflamingo",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to return this Character or one of my other Characters to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-010",
        "title": "ST03-010 Bartholomew Kuma",
        "question": "Q: After looking at 3 cards from the top of my deck, can I place 1 card on the top and 2 cards on the bottom?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. After deciding the order in which you want to place the 3 cards, you must choose whether to return all 3 cards to the top or bottom of the deck."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-010",
        "title": "ST03-010 Bartholomew Kuma",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this effect if I have 2 or less cards in my deck?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can.While looking at your deck, the number of cards in your deck is not considered 0."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-014",
        "title": "ST03-014 Marshall.D.Teach",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to return this Character or one of my other Characters to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-015",
        "title": "ST03-015 Sables",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Main] effect to return one of my Characters to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-016",
        "title": "ST03-016 Thrust Pad Cannon",
        "question": "Q: What happens to a battle if this [Counter] effect is used to return the attacking Character or the Character being attacked to the owner's hand?",
        "answer": "A: If the attacking Character or the Character being attacked is not on the field, the battle ends without anything happening."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-016",
        "title": "ST03-016 Thrust Pad Cannon",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Counter] effect to return my own Character to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-016",
        "title": "ST03-016 Thrust Pad Cannon",
        "question": "Q: If I return my own Character to my hand, can I use that Character card's Counter during that battle?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST03-017",
        "title": "ST03-017 Love-Love Mellow",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this effect to draw a card if I have 4 cards in my hand including this card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the \"draw 1 card\" effect will be activated. When an Event card is activated, that card is trashed and is not included when counting the number of cards in your hand."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-001",
        "title": "ST02-001 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid",
        "question": "Q: If my Leader has already attacked during this turn and I use this effect to set it as active, can my Leader attack again?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, your Leader can attack again."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-003",
        "title": "ST02-003 Urouge",
        "question": "Q: What happens to this Character's power if the number of Characters I have changes while this Character is battling?",
        "answer": "A: If you have 3 or more Characters at the Damage Step of the battle, the result of the battle is determined on the basis that this Character gains +2000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-003",
        "title": "ST02-003 Urouge",
        "question": "Q: Is this Character included in the count to determine \"If you have 3 or more Characters\"?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, this Character gains +2000 power if you have 3 or more Characters including this Character."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-003",
        "title": "ST02-003 Urouge",
        "question": "Q: Does this [DON!! x1] effect mean this Character gains +2000 power even during my opponent's turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, this Character gains +2000 power during your opponent's turn. This effect is effective during both players' turns."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-007",
        "title": "ST02-007 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this card’s effect to add non-green {Supernovas} type cards to my hand?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-007",
        "title": "ST02-007 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: What happens if there aren't any {Supernovas} type cards?",
        "answer": "A: You place all the cards you looked at from the top of your deck at the bottom of your deck in any order."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-007",
        "title": "ST02-007 Jewelry Bonney",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Character's \"You may rest this card\" effect on the turn it is played?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-008",
        "title": "ST02-008 Scratchmen Apoo",
        "question": "Q: Can I rest a DON!! card that is already rested?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must choose up to 1 active DON!! card from your opponent's cost area."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-008",
        "title": "ST02-008 Scratchmen Apoo",
        "question": "Q: Can I rest a DON!! card that has been given to an opponent's Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You must choose up to 1 active DON!! card from your opponent's cost area."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-009",
        "title": "ST02-009 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: If my Character has already attacked during this turn and I use this effect to set it as active, can my Character attack again?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, your Character can attack again."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-009",
        "title": "ST02-009 Trafalgar Law",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to set my Leader card as active?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. \"1 of your ... Characters\" refers only to Character cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-010",
        "title": "ST02-010 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: Can the Character attack again if this effect sets it as active?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the Character can attack again."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-010",
        "title": "ST02-010 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: If this Character battles my opponent's Character, at what point during the Battle Phase does this Character become active?",
        "answer": "A: This Character becomes active at the end of the battle if the target of the attack was a Character."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-010",
        "title": "ST02-010 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: Does this Character become active if it attacks my opponent's Leader and my opponent activates [Blocker]?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, it does."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-010",
        "title": "ST02-010 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: I declared my attack while my opponent had 5 Characters on their field, and my opponent activated the [Blocker] of \"OP01-014 Jinbe\".At this time, my opponent chose to play a red Character with a cost of 2 or less from their hand according to the [On Block] effect of \"OP01-014 Jinbe\", and trashed the Jinbe whose [Blocker] they had activated according to the rules.In this case, will my Character become active?",
        "answer": "A: No, your Character will not become active.Since the target for the attack no longer exists, the Counter Step and Damage Step will be skipped, and the battle will end. In this case, the requirement that \"this Character battles your opponent's Character\" is not resolved, so your Character cannot be set to active."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-010",
        "title": "ST02-010 Basil Hawkins",
        "question": "Q: My opponent's Character battling this Character left the field during the Attack Step, Block Step, or Counter Step due to an effect. In this case, will this Character's effect activate?",
        "answer": "A: No, it will not.This effect is activated at the end of the battle upon resolving the power comparison in the Damage Step.If the Character being battled with leaves the field in the middle of the battle (i.e., during the Attack Step, Block Step, or Counter Step), the battle is suspended at that point.In such a case, this Character's effect will not be activated because the Damage Step has not been resolved."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-013",
        "title": "ST02-013 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose not to set this Character as active at the end of my turn if it is rested with 1 or more DON!! cards given to it?",
        "answer": "A: No, you must set it as active whenever possible."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-013",
        "title": "ST02-013 Eustass\"Captain\"Kid",
        "question": "Q: If this Character is active, can I use this [End of Your Turn] effect to set this Character as active again?",
        "answer": "A: No. Nothing happens if this Character is already active."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-014",
        "title": "ST02-014 X.Drake",
        "question": "Q: Do Characters with both {Supernovas} and {Navy} types gain +2000 power?",
        "answer": "A: No, they do not. Each Character with the {Supernovas} type, {Navy} type, or both types gains +1000 power."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-015",
        "title": "ST02-015 Scalpel",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose not to set any DON!! cards as active when using this [Counter] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-015",
        "title": "ST02-015 Scalpel",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this [Trigger] effect if I don't have enough DON!! cards in my cost area?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can.In that case, you can choose to set 0 or 1 DON!! cards as active."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-016",
        "title": "ST02-016 Repel",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose not to set any DON!! cards as active when using this [Counter] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-017",
        "title": "ST02-017 Straw Sword",
        "question": "Q: Can I choose a Character that is already rested for this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. In that case, nothing happens for this [Main] effect."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-017",
        "title": "ST02-017 Straw Sword",
        "question": "Q: Can I use a {Supernovas} type Event card with this [Trigger] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. You can only play a Character card or Stage card."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST02-017",
        "title": "ST02-017 Straw Sword",
        "question": "Q: If I use this [Trigger] effect to play a card with an [On Play] effect, will the [On Play] effect be activated?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, the effect will be activated."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-001",
        "title": "ST01-001 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give a Character a DON!! card that has already been given to another Character?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot. A DON!! card that has already been given to a Character is not a \"rested DON!! card\"."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-001",
        "title": "ST01-001 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: When I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give a Character a rested DON!! card, do I need to leave the DON!! card sideways?",
        "answer": "A: No, the orientation of a DON!! card given to a Character does not matter."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-002",
        "title": "ST01-002 Usopp",
        "question": "Q: If the power of a Character blocking this Character becomes 6000 or more due to a Counter, does the target of the attack revert back to the original target?",
        "answer": "A: No. Since the [Blocker] has already been activated, the target of the attack will remain the Character that activated the [Blocker]."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-004",
        "title": "ST01-004 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: Can this Character attack if it has been rested by another effect on the turn in which it is played?",
        "answer": "A: No, a rested Character cannot attack."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-005",
        "title": "ST01-005 Jinbe",
        "question": "Q: If I have 2 of these cards on my field, can I use 1 Jinbe's [When Attacking] effect on the other Jinbe?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. \"Other than this card\" refers to the Character itself, not the card name."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-007",
        "title": "ST01-007 Nami",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this card's [Activate: Main] effect to give this card itself a DON!! card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-011",
        "title": "ST01-011 Brook",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to give only 1 rested DON!! card?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can. When a card's text states \"up to\" a specified number of cards, you can choose 0 cards."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-011",
        "title": "ST01-011 Brook",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [On Play] effect to give 1 DON!! card each to my Leader and 1 Character, or 2 different Characters?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-012",
        "title": "ST01-012 Monkey.D.Luffy",
        "question": "Q: Can my opponent activate [Blocker] if another Character attacks after this Character has attacked?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent can activate [Blocker] because it is not during the battle in which this Character's [When Attacking] effect was activated."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-013",
        "title": "ST01-013 Roronoa Zoro",
        "question": "Q: Does this [DON!! x1] effect mean this Character gains +1000 power even during my opponent's turn?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, this Character gains +1000 power during your opponent's turn. This effect is effective during both players' turns."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-015",
        "title": "ST01-015 Gum-Gum Jet Pistol",
        "question": "Q: If the power of a Character with an original power of 6000 or less becomes 7000 or more due to an effect, can it be K.O.'d by this [Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot. This effect can only K.O. a Character with a current power of 6000 or less."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-016",
        "title": "ST01-016 Diable Jambe",
        "question": "Q: Can my opponent activate [Blocker] if another Character attacks after the selected Character has attacked?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, your opponent can activate [Blocker] because it is not during the battle in which the Character you selected with this Event card is attacking."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-016",
        "title": "ST01-016 Diable Jambe",
        "question": "Q: Can this [Trigger] effect be used to K.O. Characters like \"ST01-012 Monkey.D.Luffy\" that do not have their own [Blocker] effect but have the word \"[Blocker]\" in their effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot. Only Characters with their own [Blocker] effect at the time of using this card can be K.O.'d."
    },
    {
        "id": "ST01-017",
        "title": "ST01-017 Thousand Sunny",
        "question": "Q: Can I activate this Stage's \"You may rest this Stage:\" effect on the turn it is played?",
        "answer": "A: Yes, you can."
    },
    {
        "id": "PREMIUM",
        "title": "PREMIUM BOOSTER -ONE PIECE CARD THE BEST- [PRB-01]",
        "question": "Q: Can a Character with a cost of 8 or less with an [On Play]/[When Attacking] effect gain [Rush] using this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "PREMIUM",
        "title": "PREMIUM BOOSTER -ONE PIECE CARD THE BEST- [PRB-01]",
        "question": "Q: If I play a Character without an [On Play] effect and with a cost of 8 or less during my first turn and it gains [Rush] using this [Activate: Main] effect, can that Character attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "PREMIUM",
        "title": "PREMIUM BOOSTER -ONE PIECE CARD THE BEST- [PRB-01]",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give [Rush] to \"OP05-005 Karasu\", which has the \"[On Play] If your Leader has the {Revolutionary Army} type, give up to 1 of your opponent's Leader or Character cards −1000 power during this turn\" effect when using this Leader, which does not have the {Revolutionary Army} type?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "PREMIUM",
        "title": "PREMIUM BOOSTER -ONE PIECE CARD THE BEST- [PRB-01]",
        "question": "Q: Can a Character with a cost of 8 or less and an effect such as \"[On Play] You may trash 1 card from your hand:\" gain [Rush] using this Leader's [Activate: Main] effect in the event that the activation cost was not paid and its [On Play] effect did not trigger?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "PRB01-001",
        "title": "PRB01-001 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: Can a Character with a cost of 8 or less with an [On Play]/[When Attacking] effect gain [Rush] using this [Activate: Main] effect?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "PRB01-001",
        "title": "PRB01-001 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: If I play a Character without an [On Play] effect and with a cost of 8 or less during my first turn and it gains [Rush] using this [Activate: Main] effect, can that Character attack?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "PRB01-001",
        "title": "PRB01-001 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: Can I use this [Activate: Main] effect to give [Rush] to \"OP05-005 Karasu\", which has the \"[On Play] If your Leader has the {Revolutionary Army} type, give up to 1 of your opponent's Leader or Character cards −1000 power during this turn\" effect when using this Leader, which does not have the {Revolutionary Army} type?",
        "answer": "A: No, you cannot."
    },
    {
        "id": "PRB01-001",
        "title": "PRB01-001 Sanji",
        "question": "Q: Can a Character with a cost of 8 or less and an effect such as \"[On Play] You may trash 1 card from your hand:\" gain [Rush] using this Leader's [Activate: Main] effect in the event that the activation cost was not paid and its [On Play] effect did not trigger?",
        "answer": "A: No, it cannot."
    }
]